{"_id": "9cd12842", "question": "What is the best treatment for high blood pressure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ef18295f", "question": "What is the best diet for high blood pressure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6df1691e", "question": "How do I treat extremely high blood pressure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "45be1ace", "question": "What causes high blood pressure (hypertension)?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "304cd62e", "question": "Five percent of the people have high blood pressure. Of the people with high blood pressure, 75% drink alcohol, whereas, only 50% of the people without high blood pressure drink alcohol. What percent of the drinkers have high blood pressure?", "answers": "BEST 7 NATURAL WAYS TO TREAT YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE!\nI am Carla Pierce. I want to share some high blood pressure experience from Jean Flores’s blog as follows. Jean Flores is a famous doctor in Baltimore hospital, USA.\n1- Change your diet: According to Jean Flores’s advice, There is good evidence plant-based diets high in fruits, vegetables, whole grains and legumes will lead to lower weight loss and blood pressure up to 14mmhg.\nBest foods for high blood pressure:\n-Red beets\n-Skim milk and yogurt\n-Oatmealf\n-Bananas\n-Salmon, mackerel, and fish with omega-3s\n-Seeds\n-Garlic and herbs\n-Dark chocolate\n-Pistachios\n-Olive oil\n-Pomegranates\n-Leafy greens\n-Berries\n2- Eat less.\nAs Jean Flores, Up to a certain point, getting thinner will reduce your blood pressure. Bigger mass = bigger body to pump things through = higher blood pressure.\n3- Lower your stress level:\nAs Jean Flores, stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores so, it's so important that you get some time off and reduce your stress. MeditationSecretsAZ is a good site to learn medation and eiminate your stress.\n4- Walk and exercise regularly:\nAs Jean Flores, it's a good idea to exercise for at least 20 minutes in the morning on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\n5- Taichi\nAs Jean Flores, taichi also is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. TaichiA2Z is the best site to learn Yang taichi or Wudang tai chi.\n6- Change your life style:\nAs Jean Flores, you should: do not work overtime, do not smoke, do not sleep late, sleep more, quit smoking.\n7- Yoga\nAs Jean Flores, yoga is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. YogaHandbook365 is a good site to learn many styles of yoga.\n>>Useful sources:\n1- Wikipedia: Best places to learn more high blood pressure.\n2- Best list: 21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "c252771d", "question": "Does high blood pressure (147/85) cause dizziness?", "answers": "TOP 10 NATURAL WAYS TO CURE YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE.\nI am Nancy Lopez. I want to share some high blood pressure methods from Nicole Roberts’s Twitter in the following. Nicole Roberts is a famous doctor in Miami\n1- Exercise regularly. According to Nicole Roberts’s advice, Regular exercise helps make your heart stronger and more efficient at pumping blood, which lowers the pressure in your arteries. In fact, 150 minutes of moderate exercise, such as walking, or 75 minutes of vigorous exercise, such as running, per week can help lower blood pressure and improve your heart health.\nSome exercises for high blood pressure:\n+ Go for a Swim.\n+ Take a Walk.\n+ Ride a Bike.\n+ Hit the Gym.\n+ Yoga\nUseful post: Best 3 exercises to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure in 9 minutes\n2- Reduce your sodium intake.\nAs Nicole Roberts, Salt intake is high around the world. In large part, this is due to processed and prepared foods. In many studies, salt has been linked to high blood pressure and heart events, like stroke. If you already have high blood pressure, it's worth cutting back your sodium intake to see if it makes a difference. Swap out processed foods with fresh ones and try seasoning with herbs and spices, rather than salt.\n3- Drink less alcohol.\nAs Nicole Roberts, Drinking alcohol can raise blood pressure. In fact, alcohol is linked to 16% of high blood pressure cases around the world.While some research has suggested that low-to-moderate amounts of alcohol may protect the heart, those benefits may be offset by negative effects.\n4- Eat more potassium-rich foods.\nAs Nicole Roberts, As Judy Gomez, Potassium is an important mineral. It helps your body get rid of sodium and ease pressure on your blood vessels. To get a better balance of potassium to sodium in your diet, focus on eating fewer processed foods and more fresh, whole foods.\n5- Cut back on caffeine.\nAs Nicole Roberts, If you've ever downed a cup of coffee before you've had your blood pressure taken, you'll know that caffeine causes an instant boost. If you suspect you're caffeine-sensitive, cut back to see if it lowers your blood pressure.\n6- Learn to manage stress.\nAs Nicole Roberts, Stress is a key driver of high blood pressure. When you're chronically stressed, your body is in a constant fight-or-flight mode. On a physical level, that means a faster heart rate and constricted blood vessels. When you experience stress, you might also be more likely to engage in other behaviors, such as drinking alcohol or eating unhealthy food, that can negatively affect blood pressure. MediationWayAZ is the best site to learn how to stop stress and learn mediation.\n7- Lose weight.\nAs Nicole Roberts, If you're overweight, losing weight can make a big difference for your heart health. According to a 2016 study, losing 5% of your body mass could significantly lower high blood pressure. In previous studies, losing 17 pounds (7.7 kg) was linked to lowering systolic blood pressure by 8.5 mm Hg and diastolic blood pressure by 6.5 mm Hg.\n8- Try meditation or deep breathing.\nAs Nicole Roberts, While these two behaviors could also fall under \"stress reduction techniques,\" meditation and deep breathing deserve specific mention. Both meditation and deep breathing are thought to activate the parasympathetic nervous system. This system is engaged when the body relaxes, slowing the heart rate and lowering blood pressure.\n9- Cut added sugar and refined carbs.\nAs Nicole Roberts, There's a growing body of research showing a link between added sugar and high blood pressure. In the Framingham Women's Health Study, women who drank even one soda per day had higher levels than those who drank less than one soda per day. Another study found that having one less sugar-sweetened beverage per day was linked to lower blood pressure.\n10- Eat berries.\nAs Nicole Roberts, Berries are full of more than just juicy flavor. They're also packed with polyphenols, natural plant compounds that are good for your heart. One small study had middle-aged people eat berries for eight weeks. Participants experienced improvements in different markers of heart health, including blood pressure.\n>>Useful resources:\n1- Wikipedia: Hypertension - Wikipedia\n2- Best methods: 21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "7547aadc", "question": "What foods cause high blood pressure and/or what foods help reduce high blood pressure?", "answers": "What is high blood pressure?\nBlood pressure is the force of blood pushing against blood vessel walls. The heart pumps blood into the arteries (blood vessels) which carry the blood throughout the body. High blood pressure, also called hypertension, means the pressure in your arteries is above the normal range. In most cases, no one knows what causes high blood pressure. What you eat can affect your blood pressure.\nHow does nutrition affect blood pressure?\nCertain foods can increase blood pressure.\nCertain foods can lower blood pressure.\nGaining weight can increase blood pressure.\nLosing weight can reduce blood pressure.\nWhat should I eat to control high blood pressure?\nEat foods lower in fat, salt, and calories.\nUse spices and herbs, vinegar, lemon or fruit juices instead of salt to flavour foods.\nUse less oil, butter, margarine, shortening, and salad dressings.\nWhat are some of the foods I should eat?\nSkim or 1% milk, yoghurt, Greek yoghurt (calcium-rich foods can lower blood pressure).\nLean meat.\nSkinless turkey and chicken.\nLow-salt, ready-to-eat cereals.\nCooked hot cereal (not instant).\nLow-fat and low-salt cheeses.\nFruits (fresh, frozen, or canned without added salt).\nVegetables (fresh, frozen or canned, no added salt).Richly coloured green, orange, and red items are high in potassium and minerals that help lower blood pressure.The goal is 5-9 servings of fruits and vegetables per day.\nPlain rice, pasta, and potatoes.\nBread (English muffins, bagels, rolls, and tortillas).\nLower salt \"prepared\" convenience food.\nUnsalted seeds (pumpkin, squash, sunflower) and unsalted nuts are mineral-rich foods that lower blood pressure.\nHigh\nBlood\nPressure with E.D\nWhat foods should I eat less of?\nButter and margarine.\nRegular salad dressings.\nFatty Meats.\nWhole milk dairy products.\nFried foods.\nSalted snacks.\nCanned soups.\nFast foods.\nDeli meats.\nWhat's the difference between sodium and salt?\nSalt is mostly sodium, a mineral that occurs naturally in foods. Sodium is the substance that may cause your blood pressure to increase. Other forms of sodium are also present in food. MSG (monosodium glutamate) is another example of a sodium added to food (common in Chinese food).\nHow does salt increase blood pressure?\nWhen you eat too much salt, which contains sodium, your body holds extra water to \"wash\" the salt from your body. In some people, this may cause blood pressure to rise. The added water puts stress on your heart and blood vessels.\nHow much sodium is too much?\nThe American Heart Association recommends limiting daily sodium intake no more than 1,500 milligrams. (A teaspoon of salt has about 2,400 milligrams of sodium.) Most people greatly exceed these sodium guidelines.\nHow can I reduce my sodium intake?\nDon't use table salt.\nRead nutrition labels and choose foods lower in sodium.\nChoose foods marked \"sodium-free,\" \"low sodium,\" and \"unsalted.\"\nUse salt substitutes (ask your healthcare provider first).\nDon't use lite salt as a substitute.\nRead content labels. (Contents are listed in order of greatest amount.)\nPurchase sodium-free herbs and seasoning mix like Mrs Dash®.\nWhat foods are high in sodium?\nProcessed foods such as lunch meats, sausage, bacon, and ham.\nCanned soups, bouillon, dried soup mixes.\nDeli meats.\nCondiments (catsup, soy sauce, salad dressings).\nFrozen and boxed mixes for potatoes, rice, and pasta.\nSnack foods (pretzels, popcorn, peanuts, chips).\nPickled or marinated food in brine. (Vinegar- and lemon juice-based marinades are ok.)\nWhat else should I do to change my diet?\nAvoid alcohol.\nEat a variety of foods.\nEat foods high in dietary fibre (whole grain bread, cereals, pasta, fresh fruit, and vegetables).\nComparison of Sodium in Foods\nMeats, poultry, fish, and shellfish\nFood: Milligrams (mg.) sodium\nFresh meat, 3 oz. cooked: Less than 90 mg\nShellfish, 3 oz: 100 to 325 mg\nTuna, canned, 3 oz: 300 mg\nLean ham, 3 oz.: 1,025 mg\nDairy products\nFood: Milligrams sodium\n*Whole milk, 1 cup: 120 mg\nSkim or 1% milk, 1 cup: 125 mg\n*Buttermilk (salt added), 1 cup: 260 mg\n*Swiss cheese, 1 oz: 75 mg\n*Cheddar cheese, 1 oz: 175 mg\nLow-fat cheese, 1 oz.: 150 mg\n*Cottage cheese (regular), 1/2 cup: 455 mg\nVegetables\nFood: Milligrams sodium\nFresh or frozen vegetables, and no-salt-added canned (cooked without salt), 1/2 cup: Less than 70 mg\nVegetables canned or frozen (without sauce), 1/2 cup: 55-470 mg\nTomato juice, canned, 3/4 cup: 660 mg\nBread, cereals, rice and pasta\nFood: Milligrams sodium\nBread, 1 slice: 110-175 mg\nEnglish muffin (half): 130 mg\nReady-to-eat, shredded wheat, 3/4 cup: Less than 5 mg\nCooked cereal (unsalted), 1/2 cup: Less than 5 mg\nInstant cooked cereal, 1 packet: 180 mg\nCanned soups, 1 cup: 600-1,300 mg\nConvenience foods\nFood: Milligrams sodium\nCanned and frozen main dishes, 8 oz: 500-1,570 mg\n*These can also be high in saturated fat unless low-fat or reduced fat options are purchased.\n*High in saturated fat."}
{"_id": "f0c60f16", "question": "Why is low blood pressure more harmful than high blood pressure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "cfaf7963", "question": "How do you know if your blood pressures high?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "33595bd1", "question": "Which herbs or vitamins are good to eliminate high blood pressure?", "answers": "High blood pressure needs immediate precautions to bring it down. You can easily miss its initial symptoms till it gets too late to make amends. Which is why, Ayurveda recommends to follow a controlled diet and lifestyle that can keep a check on your blood pressure throughout the day. As per Ayurveda, following dincarya (daily regime) and ritucarya (seasonal regime) is essential to oversee hypertension. So, here are some eating habits you can adopt in your every day life for controlling BP efficiently:\nAvoid spicy, sour and salty foods like chillies, ready-to-eat preparations and refined flour products. Take your meals on time and avoid binge eating after sunset.\nAdd nourishing foods like green gram, wheat, carrot, flax seeds, sesame seeds, pomegranate, Amla, beetroot, red cabbage, garlic, ghee and milk to your daily diet.\nMake it a habit to consume supper early in the evening. Incorporate sweet, astringent and bitter food sources in it as they reduce blood toxicity.\nFurther, you can top up your diet with some Ayurvedic herbs like Punarnava, Ginger etc. that can lower the blood pressure and prevent its complications. Here are some easy remedies for doing so:\nDrink dry ginger herbal tea in the morning hours, if your high blood pressure is triggered by consuming untimely meals or refrigerated food.\nConsume Amalaki or Gokshura powder/tablets every day, if you are exceedingly indulgent in junk food.\nHypertension caused by stress, anxiety or intake of alcohol/acidic food can be curbed with Arjuna and Shatavari.\nFor prolonged complaint of hypertension, drink Moringa leaf juice with honey regularly. Make sure to consult your physician for getting your dosage guidelines\nBoil some Garlic cloves in milk and drink it with honey. It is a sureshot remedy for controlling high blood pressure.\nIf you find these remedies too hassling, you can also try Nirogam’s Hypershun\ntablets. It is composed of Giloy, Ashwagandha, Mandukaparni, Vacha, Mandukpishti, Praval pishti and many more BP-regulating herbs that nourish the kidney, spleen and intestine tissues, while lowering your average blood pressure readings.\nHope this helps you to manage your BP problems better!"}
{"_id": "ad865d73", "question": "What are the natural ways to reduce high blood pressure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7f1af3f3", "question": "Can high blood pressure be cured? If not, how can one control it?", "answers": "There are two type of hypertension.\n1 Primary\n2 Secondary\nPrimary is not due to any other disease.\nCauses includes stress, sedentary life style, and mostly genetic.\nTwo types of primary hypertension, benign and malignant. Benign is easy to treat since bp won't be very high as in malignant, leads to disease after very long time.\nMalignant is more dangerous, where blood pressure stays very high like 200/120, 230/140 and some time as less as 160/100. It's generally difficult to treat. All end Organ damage will manifest within 5 years if bp is not controlled adequately.\nSecondary hypertension is due to any abnormal changes or disease of the organs such as kidney, nervous system or blood vessel, increased amount of thyroid hormone in the blood, etc.\nOkay, first no cure.\nCan be controlled and bp may become normal.\nNatural:\nExcercise regularly.\nAerobic\nCycling and/or jogging\nYoga and meditation\nDASH diet\nSalt restriction (<2gms of sodium/day)\nFruits/veg (adequate Potassium and magnesium)\n- this is N/A for patients with end\nstage kidney failure\nDecrease dietary fat intake\nIncreased dietary fibre intake\nFluid restriction (only for patients with end stage kidney failure)\nOthers drink adequate amount of water\nStay stress free.\nStop smoking.\nTry to avoid/Reduce coffee consumption\nTry to avoid/Reduce alcohol consumption to (<20ml/day)\nBp will be maintained very well in most casses by the above methods.\nMedications:\nAnti hypertensive drugs\nSuch as depin, clonidepin, ramipril, enalopril, lisindopril, thiazides etc..\nAlong with drugs to decrease the blood pressure Drugs to control the disease that causes hypertension is also given in patients with secondary hypertension.\nPlease follow your docs prescription for drugs, taking medications that is meant to decrease your bp may decrease it too low if taken at high dosages/multiple drugs at a time. They have various unwanted side effects also. Hence not to be taken without consultation.\nNatural ways are applicable for most people with hypertension, and are almost always safe. May not be easy to follow all, may not be easy to practice regularly. May not be effective if bp is very high due to secondary cause for example a condition called renal artery stenosis (where artery of kidney becomes narrow), where a drug or intervention by a professional is compulsory."}
{"_id": "3531b734", "question": "What precautions should I take during high blood pressure?", "answers": "TOP 7 WAYS TO CURE YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE WITHOUT MEDICATION!\nI am Naomi Wong. Let me share some high blood pressure methods from Wendy Long’s Twitter as follows. Wendy Long is a famous doctor in Fresno hospital, USA.\n1- Change your diet: According to Wendy Long’s advice, There is good evidence plant-based diets high in fruits, vegetables, whole grains and legumes will lead to lower weight loss and blood pressure up to 14mmhg.\nBest foods for high blood pressure:\n-Red beets\n-Skim milk and yogurt\n-Oatmealf\n-Bananas\n-Salmon, mackerel, and fish with omega-3s\n-Seeds\n-Garlic and herbs\n-Dark chocolate\n-Pistachios\n-Olive oil\n-Pomegranates\n-Leafy greens\n-Berries\n2- Eat less.\nAs Wendy Long, Up to a certain point, getting thinner will reduce your blood pressure. Bigger mass = bigger body to pump things through = higher blood pressure.\n3- Lower your stress level:\nAs Wendy Long, stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores so, it's so important that you get some time off and reduce your stress. MeditationSecretsAZ is a good site to learn medation and eiminate your stress.\n4- Walk and exercise regularly:\nAs Wendy Long, it's a good idea to exercise for at least 20 minutes in the morning on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\n5- Taichi\nAs Wendy Long, taichi also is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. TaichiA2Z is the best site to learn Yang taichi or Wudang tai chi.\n6- Change your life style:\nAs Wendy Long, you should: do not work overtime, do not smoke, do not sleep late, sleep more, quit smoking.\n7- Yoga\nAs Wendy Long, yoga is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. YogaHandbook365 is a good site to learn many styles of yoga.\n>>Useful sources:\n1- Wikipedia: Best places to learn more high blood pressure.\n2- Best list: 27 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "1e415e06", "question": "How best can you lower high blood pressure without medication?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c210d191", "question": "What is high blood pressure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6f2187df", "question": "Can high blood pressure kill?", "answers": "TOP 6 WAYS TO LOWER YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE WITHOUT MEDICATION!\nMy name is Amanda Flores. I would like to share some high blood pressure techniques from Ashley Hall’s WordPress blog below. Ashley Hall is a famous doctor in Tucson hospital, USA.\n1- Change your diet: According to Ashley Hall’s advice, if you follow a good diet, you can reduce your blood pressure by up to 14mmhg.\na- Leafy greens:\n• turnip greens\n• collard greens\n• spinach\n• beet greens\n• Swiss chard\n• romaine lettuce\n• arugula\n• kale\nb- Berries\nc- Red beets\nd- Skim milk and yogurt\ne- Oatmeal\nf- Bananas\ng- Salmon, mackerel, and fish with omega-3s\nh- Seeds\ni- Garlic and herbs\nj- Dark chocolate\nk- Pistachios\nl- Olive oil\nm- Pomegranates\n2- Lower your stress level:\nAs Ashley Hall, stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores so, it's so important that you get some time off and reduce your stress. MeditationSecretsAZ is a good site to learn medation and eiminate your stress\n3- Walk and exercise regularly:\nAs Ashley Hall, it's a good idea to exercise for at least 25 minutes in the morning on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\n4- Yoga\nAs Ashley Hall, yoga is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. YogaHandbook365 is a good site to learn many styles of yoga.\n5- Change your life style:\nAs Ashley Hall, you should: do not work overtime, do not smoke, do not sleep late, sleep more, quit smoking.\n6- Taichi\nAs Ashley Hall, taichi also is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. TaichiA2Z is the best site to learn Yang taichi or Wudang tai chi.\n>>Useful sources:\n1- Exercise methods: 22 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure\n2- Wikipedia: Best places to learn more high blood pressure."}
{"_id": "a2649520", "question": "What is best excercise for lowering high blood pressure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "984aaea9", "question": "What is the one food that kill high blood pressure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "cc121c53", "question": "Have any of you cured yourself of high blood pressure?", "answers": "My BP is about 190/105 when i went to doctor , she gave me meds which i took for one week only and then i stop taking because of many side effects and still my BP will not go down, stays at 160/100 during medication.\ni search the internet including quora for answers and started exercise and only vegs salad for dinner.\ni took also magnesium supplement (500 mg) daily..so it went down to 150/100 for the first week, then started to go down to 150/90 after two weeks..and i added 30 mins exercise walk in the morning from previous 30 minutes aerobic exercise in the evening with 2 hours walking during weekend (friday here)..\nit started to go to 140/90…after a month and then 130 /90 going when i approach two months of diet, exercise and magnesium..\nnow it is 120/80 after more than two months"}
{"_id": "ec053a06", "question": "What are the symptoms of high-blood pressure ?", "answers": "Most people with high blood pressure have no symptoms at all, that's why it's called the silent killer, since in the long run it can damage your heart, kidneys, brain, eyes, causing heart attacks, heart failure, strokes, even blindness.\nOnly in very severe high blood pressure (Hypertensive emergency\n) causing your brain to swell it can cause headache, nausea, confusion, paresthesia (Hypertensive encephalopathy\n), and if the eyes are severely damaged you get vision problems (Hypertensive retinopathy\n)\nSo only by measuring correctly you will know your blood pressure.\nMeasuring blood pressure is another problem, many people who on one occasion had too high a blood pressure didn't have it when blood pressure was taken at a later moment, we call it White coat hypertension\n. In the large Australian therapeutic trial in mild hypertension study published in The Lancet on 14 June 1980 they found that even after 3 measurements of too high a blood pressure 504 (12,8%) of the in total 3932 participants had a blood pressure below the inclusion range at the 4th, 5th etc. measurement so weren't that hypertensive at all. So before treating high blood pressure just make sure it really is too high.\nUsually the first measurement is falsely high, we repeat measuring blood pressure until we have two measurements within 5% of each other, the mean of which we consider the right measurement.\nYou can help your doc by measuring your own blood pressure at home using a validated blood pressure monitor, following the recommendation above, and writing the measurements down.\nHere you find a validated list (in green) of blood pressure monitors:\ndabl Educational Trust|Monitors for Self-measurement of\nBlood\nPressure (SBPM)\n\nI would go for an upper arm blood pressure monitor. They costs around US$ 100,- Don't just buy a cheap one, because they aren't reliable so are no good.\nBy now we have scientifically proven non pharmacological means to treat high blood pressure, being:\nloosing weight (most important)\n3-4 times a week 30-60 minutes of (aerobic and isometric) exercises\nrelaxation exercises\nless than 1 alcoholic drink a day\navoid salt in the food (unfortunately not all hypertensives are salt sensitive, so works only FOR some) strive for 2 to max 6 grams of salt a day in your food\ndon't smoke: smoking will damage your cardiovascular system more than the protection you gain from anti-hypertensive therapy.\nsome research is being done on supplementing potassium, calcium, omega 3 fatty acids, low fat diets etc.\nSee:\nNon-pharmacological treatment of hypertension.\n\nAlternative Treatments for\nHigh\nBlood\nPressure\n\nhttp://www.google.nl/url?sa=t&rct=j&q=&esrc=s&source=web&cd=2&ved=0CDkQFjAB&url=http%3A%2F%2Fjournals.cambridge.org%2Fproduction%2Faction%2FcjoGetFulltext%3Ffulltextid%3D678648&ei=hTREUb-sEe2b1AW7u4C4Dw&usg=AFQjCNE6THQq53zkTGnenKwjS6p1jW-eBg&bvm=bv.43828540,d.d2k\nIf these aren' effective enough meds will be added."}
{"_id": "9ab90e09", "question": "What are the reasons for high blood sugar?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6addad0a", "question": "Does egg leads to constipation?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c06bde4a", "question": "Why can high blood pressure lead to kidney failure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ab85e841", "question": "What is the correlation between high blood pressure, high cholesterol and high blood sugar?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "55408d4c", "question": "How long can one live with high blood pressure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "039e321b", "question": "What does high blood pressure have to do with brain health?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c16ef605", "question": "Does beet root juice reduce high blood pressure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4db9b3a0", "question": "Can high blood pressure cause you to feel more tired?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7e0e1031", "question": "Why high blood pressure could leads to stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "33f625de", "question": "Why a person suffering from high blood pressure sweat a lot?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "9d378a27", "question": "What foods must I avoid to lower blood pressure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "adcb93b8", "question": "Diabetes: Can people sense high blood sugar?", "answers": "I have answered very few, if any, questions on Quora over the past few months and have only made a handful of comments. And I have thought about this for quite some time but have finally decided to exit Quora, and I am taking my answers with me.\nWhen people would ask me what Quora is I would tell them it is a mixture somewhere between Wikipedia and Yahoo Answers. Unfortunately, in my experience, the \"Yahoo Answers\" portion seems to be growing.\nThe worst thing of all, though, is the Quora Partners program. It seems backwards to me to be rewarding people for asking questions as opposed to providing answers. Yes, questions are important as they often are where a pathway to knowledge begins. But questions are a jumping off point and if no one jumps then no journey is ever taken.\nIt is like someone knowing that a treasure is buried in a field and announcing, \"Anyone who brings a shovel to this field will get a reward.\" Thousands, even millions of shovels are provided, with some people making hundreds of trips and getting rewarded for all the shovels they are carrying. A few enterprising individuals even find a way to bring the same shovel multiple times.\nWhat of those people who pick up a shovel and dig, eventually uncovering the treasures?\n\"Sorry, we are only giving rewards to those who are providing shovels. Thank you for revealing this treasure, though.\"\nTo me, that's just backwards.\nSo, I am leaving. In addition, though some will disagree with my choice, I am reburying my treasures.\nThank you to all who upvoted my answers; what I am doing may seem that I am ungrateful to you but please be assured I very much appreciate the support and encouragement you provided.\n- Mac"}
{"_id": "aa9c3abd", "question": "What is the strongest high blood pressure medicine in the world?", "answers": "TOP 6 WAYS TO LOWER YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE WITHOUT MEDICATION!\nMy name is Geneva Brewer. I found some high blood pressure tips from Olga Lynch’s Facebook as followings. Olga Lynch is a famous doctor in Plano hospital, USA.\n1- Change your diet: According to Olga Lynch’s advice, if you follow a good diet, you can reduce your blood pressure by up to 14mmhg.\n2- Lower your stress level:\nAs Olga Lynch, stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores so, it's so important that you get some time off and reduce your stress. MeditationSecretsAZ is a good site to learn medation and eiminate your stress\n3- Walk and exercise regularly:\nAs Olga Lynch, it's a good idea to exercise for at least 25 minutes in the morning on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\n4- Yoga\nAs Olga Lynch, yoga is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. YogaHandbook365 is a good site to learn many styles of yoga.\n5- Change your life style:\nAs Olga Lynch, you should: do not work overtime, do not smoke, do not sleep late, sleep more, quit smoking.\n6- Taichi\nAs Olga Lynch, taichi also is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. TaichiA2Z is the best site to learn Yang taichi or Wudang tai chi.\n>>Useful sources:\n1- Exercise methods: 22 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure\n2- Wikipedia: Best places to learn more high blood pressure."}
{"_id": "491e1d22", "question": "Can a person with high blood pressure exercise?", "answers": "If you have high blood pressure, your doctor or nurse may suggest that you try to become more active to lower it. However, you may be worried that regular exercise will increase your blood pressure to dangerous levels.\nIt is true that physical activity (exercise) will cause your blood pressure to rise for a short time. However, when you stop the activity, your blood pressure should soon return to normal. The quicker it does this, the fitter you are likely to be.\nMost people with high blood pressure should be able to increase their physical activity levels quite safely.\nHowever, if your blood pressure is relatively high, your doctor or nurse may prefer to lower it with medicines before starting you on an exercise programme. If your blood pressure is very high, you should not start any new activity without consulting your doctor.\nResearchers at the Pennington Biomedical Research Center in Baton Rouge, La., studied about 400 women between 45 and 75. All were overweight or obese, sedentary, and had high blood pressure. Researchers divided the women into four groups, three of which exercised at different intensity levels and for different lengths of time. The fourth group remained sedentary.\nSix months later, all three groups of active women had improved blood pressure readings, the researchers found. The numbers for the group that did the most intense exercise were only slightly better than those of the group that worked out least intensely. Though the women did not lose weight, they benefited greatly from better improving their cardiovascular fitness.\nEveryone — especially those with health conditions such as diabetes, heart disease, and high blood pressure — should get at least 2 and a half hours of modest exercise every week.\nOne of the best and easiest exercises you can do is walk. You can walk anywhere, and it doesn’t require any equipment beyond a good pair of sneakers.\nMike Minter, 813 964 7100, www.MintcoFinancial.com\nLife Insurance is possible for people with diabetes, high blood pressure, dementia."}
{"_id": "1c0515d6", "question": "My blood pressure is 140/70. Is it high?", "answers": "Okay, good question! Actually, I'm a medical student hope my answer would be helpful to you!\nWhat actually blood pressure is? It is the pressure which is exerted by the blood on the arteries ( in which the blood is flowing ) during the contraction of the left ventricle.\nIf we talk about the normal blood pressure range it's like - 90/60 to 120 / 80…its the range given on the books…but nowadays due to our living style, the type of food we eat, the type of work we engaged with etc has influenced it…140 / 70 is considered normal in adults due to all the factors I discussed above…\nBut if it is above 160/100( hypertension ) and below 80/60 ( hypotension ) then it could be harmful and can lead to cardiovascular diseases…Both the conditions are fatal…\nHere I'm discussing the preventions.\nFor hypertensive patients -\n1- change your living style.\n2 - avoid more consumption of salt as salt has the property to cause water retention in the body hence cause increased blood volume and therefore increased blood pressure.\n3- Maintain our weight as overweight causes hypertension.\n4- exercise daily.\n5- reduce stress as it causes secretion of some hormones that cause high bp.\n6- Avoid the consumption of alcohol and say no to smoking.\n7- say no to fast food…as they cause accumulation of fat/cholesterol in the blood vessels causing their narrowing hence increased blood pressure.\n8- eat daily a slice of garlic in the morning as garlic has the property to reduce the amount of cholesterol/ fat accumulated in the blood vessels ( by melting )\nThanks!\nThis is my first answer on quora since have joined here…\nDo forgive all my mistakes..Hope this would be helpful!"}
{"_id": "8473b2de", "question": "What exactly is high blood pressure and low blood pressure?", "answers": "TOP 7 NATURAL WAYS TO CURE YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE!\nMy name is Debra Hill. Hi friends, let me show some high blood pressure tips from Ashley Hall’s Facebook as followings. Ashley Hall is a famous doctor in Milwaukee hospital, USA.\n1- Change your diet: According to Ashley Hall’s advice, There is good evidence plant-based diets high in fruits, vegetables, whole grains and legumes will lead to lower weight loss and blood pressure up to 14mmhg.\nBest foods for high blood pressure:\n-Red beets\n-Skim milk and yogurt\n-Oatmealf\n-Bananas\n-Salmon, mackerel, and fish with omega-3s\n-Seeds\n-Garlic and herbs\n-Dark chocolate\n-Pistachios\n-Olive oil\n-Pomegranates\n-Leafy greens\n-Berries\n2- Eat less.\nAs Ashley Hall, Up to a certain point, getting thinner will reduce your blood pressure. Bigger mass = bigger body to pump things through = higher blood pressure.\n3- Lower your stress level:\nAs Ashley Hall, stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores so, it's so important that you get some time off and reduce your stress. MeditationSecretsAZ is a good site to learn medation and eiminate your stress.\n4- Walk and exercise regularly:\nAs Ashley Hall, it's a good idea to exercise for at least 20 minutes in the morning on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\n5- Taichi\nAs Ashley Hall, taichi also is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. TaichiA2Z is the best site to learn Yang taichi or Wudang tai chi.\n6- Change your life style:\nAs Ashley Hall, you should: do not work overtime, do not smoke, do not sleep late, sleep more, quit smoking.\n7- Yoga\nAs Ashley Hall, yoga is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. YogaHandbook365 is a good site to learn many styles of yoga.\n>>Useful sources:\n1- Wikipedia: Best places to learn more high blood pressure.\n2- Best list: 27 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "11356e77", "question": "Is it safe to do the keto diet while having high blood pressure?", "answers": "I am Ellen Cole. Hi friends, let me show some high blood pressure experience from Suzanne Stevens’s blog: Top 8 tips that can help to lower your high blood pressure in just 9 mins. Suzanne Stevens is a famous blogger about blood pressure.\nSuzanne Stevens’s Tip 1: Lose weight. Being overweight means that your heart has to pump blood to a larger body mass, which makes the heart work harder. Losing weight reduces the workload. “Plus, your heart will be better able to respond to circumstances that do require more work, like exercise,” says Dr. Zusman.\nSuzanne Stevens’s Tip 2: Exercise. Any activity that gets your heart pumping faster and your lungs working harder is one of the best ways to lower high blood pressure. “It improves the blood vessels’ ability to open and close, which improves blood flow,” says Dr. Zusman. Aim for at least 150 minutes of moderate-intensity activity per week, such as brisk walking.\nSuzanne Stevens’s Tip 3: Reduce your stress. Chronic stress may contribute to high blood pressure. More research is needed to determine the effects of chronic stress on blood pressure. Occasional stress also can contribute to high blood pressure if you react to stress by eating unhealthy food, drinking alcohol or smoking.\nSuzanne Stevens’s Tip 4: Reduce sodium in your diet\nSuzanne Stevens’s Tip 5: Control underlying conditions.\nSuzanne Stevens’s Tip 6: Stop caffeine.\nSuzanne Stevens’s Tip 7: Limit alcohol intake.\nSuzanne Stevens’s Tip 8: Stop smoking.\nUseful resources:\n1- Wikipedia: Hypertension - Wikipedia\n2- HypertensionTips68: Exercise tips for\nhigh\nblood\npressure\n3- Yoga solution from Quora: What are best yoga to control blood pressure?\n4- HBPtips365: 21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "165f55b3", "question": "Can people with high blood pressure donate blood?", "answers": "BEST 7 NATURAL WAYS TO TREAT YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE!\nMy name is Mattie Carlson. I would like to share some high blood pressure techniques from Amelia Joseph’s WordPress blog as followings. Amelia Joseph is a famous doctor in Sacramento hospital, USA.\n1- Change your diet: According to Amelia Joseph’s advice, There is good evidence plant-based diets high in fruits, vegetables, whole grains and legumes will lead to lower weight loss and blood pressure up to 14mmhg.\nBest foods for high blood pressure:\n-Red beets\n-Skim milk and yogurt\n-Oatmealf\n-Bananas\n-Salmon, mackerel, and fish with omega-3s\n-Seeds\n-Garlic and herbs\n-Dark chocolate\n-Pistachios\n-Olive oil\n-Pomegranates\n-Leafy greens\n-Berries\n2- Eat less.\nAs Amelia Joseph, Up to a certain point, getting thinner will reduce your blood pressure. Bigger mass = bigger body to pump things through = higher blood pressure.\n3- Lower your stress level:\nAs Amelia Joseph, stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores so, it's so important that you get some time off and reduce your stress. MeditationSecretsAZ is a good site to learn medation and eiminate your stress.\n4- Walk and exercise regularly:\nAs Amelia Joseph, it's a good idea to exercise for at least 20 minutes in the morning on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\n5- Taichi\nAs Amelia Joseph, taichi also is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. TaichiA2Z is the best site to learn Yang taichi or Wudang tai chi.\n6- Change your life style:\nAs Amelia Joseph, you should: do not work overtime, do not smoke, do not sleep late, sleep more, quit smoking.\n7- Yoga\nAs Amelia Joseph, yoga is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. YogaHandbook365 is a good site to learn many styles of yoga.\n>>Useful sources:\n1- Wikipedia: Best places to learn more high blood pressure.\n2- Best list: 21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "3a7ebbdb", "question": "What has high blood pressure done to you?", "answers": "I am Kara LaraI found some high blood pressure methods from Lila Goodman’s Twitter: Top 10 ways that can help to treat your high blood pressure. Lila Goodman is a famous blogger about blood pressure.\nLila Goodman’s Method 1. Change your diet: If you follow a good diet, you can reduce your blood pressure by up to 14mmHg.\nMethod 2. Control your weight. If you are overweight, losing even a few pounds like 4 kgs can help a lot.\nMethod 3. Walk and exercise regularly. It is a good method to exercise for at least 30 mins on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\nUseful source: Excercise tips to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure\nLila Goodman’s Method 4. Use less salt: According to doctors, you should not take more than 1.4 grams of salt per day so that you may want to use salt sparingly to keep your blood pressure normal.\nMethod 5. Lower your stress level.\nMethod 6. You need to religiously take your maintenance medications to control your hypertension as your doctor has prescribed it.\nMethod 7. Quit smoking.\nMethod 8. Drink less alcohol.\nMethod 9. Eat more potassium-rich foods.\nMethod 10. Cut back on caffeine."}
{"_id": "edf4e3e3", "question": "What happens if you ignore a diagnosis of high blood pressure?", "answers": "My name is Alice Gomez. Hi friends, let me show some high blood pressure techniques from Lori Reyes’s WordPress blog: Top 8 tips that can help to lower your high blood pressure in just 9 mins. Lori Reyes is a famous blogger about blood pressure.\nLori Reyes’s Tip 1: Lose weight. Being overweight means that your heart has to pump blood to a larger body mass, which makes the heart work harder. Losing weight reduces the workload. “Plus, your heart will be better able to respond to circumstances that do require more work, like exercise,” says Dr. Zusman.\nLori Reyes’s Tip 2: Exercise. Any activity that gets your heart pumping faster and your lungs working harder is one of the best ways to lower high blood pressure. “It improves the blood vessels’ ability to open and close, which improves blood flow,” says Dr. Zusman. Aim for at least 150 minutes of moderate-intensity activity per week, such as brisk walking.\nLori Reyes’s Tip 3: Reduce your stress. Chronic stress may contribute to high blood pressure. More research is needed to determine the effects of chronic stress on blood pressure. Occasional stress also can contribute to high blood pressure if you react to stress by eating unhealthy food, drinking alcohol or smoking.\nLori Reyes’s Tip 4: Reduce sodium in your diet\nLori Reyes’s Tip 5: Control underlying conditions.\nLori Reyes’s Tip 6: Stop caffeine.\nLori Reyes’s Tip 7: Limit alcohol intake.\nLori Reyes’s Tip 8: Stop smoking.\nUseful resources:\n1- Wikipedia: Hypertension - Wikipedia\n2- HypertensionTips68: Exercise tips for\nhigh\nblood\npressure\n3- Yoga solution from Quora: What are best yoga to control blood pressure?\n4- HBPtips365: 21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "f2c72b97", "question": "What supplements are good for high blood pressure?", "answers": "BEST 7 NATURAL WAYS TO TREAT YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE!\nMy name is Jodi Frazier. I found some high blood pressure secrets from Lorraine Wells’s site below. Lorraine Wells is a famous doctor in Arlington hospital, USA.\n1- Change your diet: According to Lorraine Wells’s advice, There is good evidence plant-based diets high in fruits, vegetables, whole grains and legumes will lead to lower weight loss and blood pressure up to 14mmhg.\nBest foods for high blood pressure:\n-Red beets\n-Skim milk and yogurt\n-Oatmealf\n-Bananas\n-Salmon, mackerel, and fish with omega-3s\n-Seeds\n-Garlic and herbs\n-Dark chocolate\n-Pistachios\n-Olive oil\n-Pomegranates\n-Leafy greens\n-Berries\n2- Eat less.\nAs Lorraine Wells, Up to a certain point, getting thinner will reduce your blood pressure. Bigger mass = bigger body to pump things through = higher blood pressure.\n3- Lower your stress level:\nAs Lorraine Wells, stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores so, it's so important that you get some time off and reduce your stress. MeditationSecretsAZ is a good site to learn medation and eiminate your stress.\n4- Walk and exercise regularly:\nAs Lorraine Wells, it's a good idea to exercise for at least 20 minutes in the morning on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\n5- Taichi\nAs Lorraine Wells, taichi also is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. TaichiA2Z is the best site to learn Yang taichi or Wudang tai chi.\n6- Change your life style:\nAs Lorraine Wells, you should: do not work overtime, do not smoke, do not sleep late, sleep more, quit smoking.\n7- Yoga\nAs Lorraine Wells, yoga is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. YogaHandbook365 is a good site to learn many styles of yoga.\n>>Useful sources:\n1- Wikipedia: Best places to learn more high blood pressure.\n2- Best list: 21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "74c7e12e", "question": "Does every high blood pressure patient get a heart attack?", "answers": "I would like to share some hypertension secrets from Tonya Spencer’s blog: Best 6 secrets to cure high blood pressure effectively. Tonya Spencer is a famous blogger about blood pressure.\nBelow are some of Tonya Spencer’s advice, I hope it helps.\n1- Change your diet: If you follow a good diet, you can reduce your blood pressure by up to 14mmHg.\n2- Control your weight: Your weight has a significant impact on your blood pressure so, if you are overweight, losing even a few pounds like 4 kgs can help a lot.\n3- Use less salt: According to doctors, you should not take more than 1.4 grams of salt per day so that you may want to use salt sparingly to keep your blood pressure normal.\n4- Lower your stress level: Stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores so, it’s important that you get some time off and reduce your stress.\n5- Walk and exercise regularly: It’s a good idea to exercise for at least 30 minutes in the morning on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\n6- Learn from HypertensionSolution888 .club: HypertensionSolution888 is a 3-exercises program that can help to lower your high blood pressure in 2 weeks."}
{"_id": "2386ede7", "question": "Does chronic kidney disease cause high blood pressure, or does high blood pressure cause chronic kidney disease?", "answers": "TOP 6 WAYS TO LOWER YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE WITHOUT MEDICATION!\nI am Alicia Webb. Hi friends, let me show some high blood pressure experience from Ellen Butler’s blog in the following. Ellen Butler is a famous doctor in San Antonio hospital, USA.\n1- Change your diet: According to Ellen Butler’s advice, if you follow a good diet, you can reduce your blood pressure by up to 14mmhg.\n2- Lower your stress level:\nAs Ellen Butler, stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores so, it's so important that you get some time off and reduce your stress. MeditationSecretsAZ is a good site to learn medation and eiminate your stress\n3- Walk and exercise regularly:\nAs Ellen Butler, it's a good idea to exercise for at least 25 minutes in the morning on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\n4- Yoga\nAs Ellen Butler, yoga is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. YogaHandbook365 is a good site to learn many styles of yoga.\n5- Change your life style:\nAs Ellen Butler, you should: do not work overtime, do not smoke, do not sleep late, sleep more, quit smoking.\n6- Taichi\nAs Ellen Butler, taichi also is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. TaichiA2Z is the best site to learn Yang taichi or Wudang tai chi.\n>>Useful sources:\n1- Exercise methods: 22 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure\n2- Wikipedia: Best places to learn more high blood pressure."}
{"_id": "9568b0ac", "question": "What type of salt is recommended for high blood pressure sufferers?", "answers": "All real salt is sodium, whether it is rock salt, from the Mediterranean or wherever, so just as “bad”. Not adding salt to one’s cooking at all, avoiding salted foods like bacon, sausages etc., having low salt bread and milk will lower your salt intake to around 3 - 6 grams daily.\nThis is NOT something you want to ignore (especially when it can be treated). If you’re struggling with blood pressure take a look at this: Blood\nPressure Exercises VSL cb\nTh mineral sodium i a component f salt. Yur nerves nd muscles require sodium fr proper functioning, nd ur kidneys require it — lng with potassium — fr osmosis, th process b whih extra fluid i removed frm ur blood. Whn u consume excess sodium, ur bd retains fluid, whih increases ur blood volume nd pressure.\nSodium-replacement salt i recommended fr people suffering frm high blood pressure. Th sodium-replacement salts taste th m nrml table salt but u potassium intd f sodium a key ingredient. In fact, th m hl t lower blood pressure bu f th helpful effects f potassium."}
{"_id": "07a8c729", "question": "What causes high blood pressure in teenagers?", "answers": "It was once believed that most cases of high blood pressure in teenagers were caused by underlying problems with the heart or kidneys. Further research has shown that this is not true, and it now appears that teenagers develop high blood pressure in approximately the same proportions as adults.\nIn other words, most cases of high blood pressure in teenagers are classified as primary hypertension. As with adults, the underlying causes of primary hypertension are not entirely understood.\nTime of day: Blood pressure changes throughout the day.\nPhysical activity: Blood pressure is usually higher during and right after exercise.\nEmotions: Feeling angry, afraid, or happy can affect blood pressure: Feeling anxious or nervous at the healthcare provider's office may also affect blood pressure.\nAge, height, weight, and gender: Blood pressure is lower in infants compared with older children. Taller children usually have higher blood\npressure than shorter children: Overweight or obese children are more likely to have high blood pressure. And boys usually have slightly higher blood pressure than girls.\nIn these patients, angioplasty with stent placement may greatly improve or cure the high blood pressure and reduce the need for medicines. In some patients, kidney function is threatened by the blockage, and interventional radiology\nmay prevent the need for dialysis."}
{"_id": "2ee7fb0e", "question": "Why is it dangerous to have high blood pressure when you are pregnant?", "answers": "TOP 6 WAYS TO LOWER YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE WITHOUT MEDICATION!\nMy name is Iris Bates. Let me share some high blood pressure tips from Esther Romero’s Facebook below. Esther Romero is a famous doctor in New York hospital, USA.\n1- Change your diet: According to Esther Romero’s advice, if you follow a good diet, you can reduce your blood pressure by up to 14mmhg.\n2- Lower your stress level:\nAs Esther Romero, stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores so, it's so important that you get some time off and reduce your stress. MeditationSecretsAZ is a good site to learn medation and eiminate your stress\n3- Walk and exercise regularly:\nAs Esther Romero, it's a good idea to exercise for at least 25 minutes in the morning on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\n4- Yoga\nAs Esther Romero, yoga is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. YogaHandbook365 is a good site to learn many styles of yoga.\n5- Change your life style:\nAs Esther Romero, you should: do not work overtime, do not smoke, do not sleep late, sleep more, quit smoking.\n6- Taichi\nAs Esther Romero, taichi also is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. TaichiA2Z is the best site to learn Yang taichi or Wudang tai chi.\n>>Useful sources:\n1- Exercise methods: 22 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure\n2- Wikipedia: Best places to learn more high blood pressure."}
{"_id": "31216526", "question": "Do emotions cause high blood pressure or are emotions an expression of high blood pressure?", "answers": "I would like to share some hypertension techniques from Judith Turner’s site: Best 5 secrets to cure high blood pressure effectively. Judith Turner is a famous blogger about blood pressure.\nBelow are some Judith Turner’s advice, I hope it helps.\nChange your diet: If you follow a good diet, you can reduce your blood pressure by up to 14mmHg.\nControl your weight: Your weight has a significant impact on your blood pressure so, if you are overweight, losing even a few pounds like 4 kg can help a lot.\n+ Use less salt: According to doctors, you should not take more than 1.4 grams of salt per day so that you may want to use salt sparingly to keep your blood pressure normal.\n+ Lower your stress leve: Stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores. So, it’s important that you get some time off and reduce your stress.\nWalk and exercise regularly: It’s a good idea to exercise for at least 30 minutes in the morning on a regular basis. This can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\nLearn from HypertensionSolution888 .club: HypertensionSolution888 is a 3-exercises program that can help to low your high blood pressure in 2 weeks."}
{"_id": "6fc903f9", "question": "What is the ketogenic diet's effect on blood pressure?", "answers": "BEST 7 NATURAL WAYS TO TREAT YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE!\nI am Nellie Estrada. I found some high blood pressure tricks from Ruby Bailey’s website as follows. Ruby Bailey is a famous doctor in Henderson hospital, USA.\n1- Change your diet: According to Ruby Bailey’s advice, There is good evidence plant-based diets high in fruits, vegetables, whole grains and legumes will lead to lower weight loss and blood pressure up to 14mmhg.\nBest foods for high blood pressure:\n-Red beets\n-Skim milk and yogurt\n-Oatmealf\n-Bananas\n-Salmon, mackerel, and fish with omega-3s\n-Seeds\n-Garlic and herbs\n-Dark chocolate\n-Pistachios\n-Olive oil\n-Pomegranates\n-Leafy greens\n-Berries\n2- Eat less.\nAs Ruby Bailey, Up to a certain point, getting thinner will reduce your blood pressure. Bigger mass = bigger body to pump things through = higher blood pressure.\n3- Lower your stress level:\nAs Ruby Bailey, stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores so, it's so important that you get some time off and reduce your stress. MeditationSecretsAZ is a good site to learn medation and eiminate your stress.\n4- Walk and exercise regularly:\nAs Ruby Bailey, it's a good idea to exercise for at least 20 minutes in the morning on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\n5- Taichi\nAs Ruby Bailey, taichi also is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. TaichiA2Z is the best site to learn Yang taichi or Wudang tai chi.\n6- Change your life style:\nAs Ruby Bailey, you should: do not work overtime, do not smoke, do not sleep late, sleep more, quit smoking.\n7- Yoga\nAs Ruby Bailey, yoga is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. YogaHandbook365 is a good site to learn many styles of yoga.\n>>Useful sources:\n1- Wikipedia: Best places to learn more high blood pressure.\n2- Best list: 21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "8367c2e0", "question": "Does high blood pressure cause lethargy?", "answers": "BEST 7 NATURAL WAYS TO TREAT YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE!\nMy name is Melinda Perkins. Let me share some high blood pressure tips from Jane Collins’s Facebook below. Jane Collins is a famous doctor in Tampa hospital, USA.\n1- Change your diet: According to Jane Collins’s advice, There is good evidence plant-based diets high in fruits, vegetables, whole grains and legumes will lead to lower weight loss and blood pressure up to 14mmhg.\nBest foods for high blood pressure:\n-Red beets\n-Skim milk and yogurt\n-Oatmealf\n-Bananas\n-Salmon, mackerel, and fish with omega-3s\n-Seeds\n-Garlic and herbs\n-Dark chocolate\n-Pistachios\n-Olive oil\n-Pomegranates\n-Leafy greens\n-Berries\n2- Eat less.\nAs Jane Collins, Up to a certain point, getting thinner will reduce your blood pressure. Bigger mass = bigger body to pump things through = higher blood pressure.\n3- Lower your stress level:\nAs Jane Collins, stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores so, it's so important that you get some time off and reduce your stress. MeditationSecretsAZ is a good site to learn medation and eiminate your stress.\n4- Walk and exercise regularly:\nAs Jane Collins, it's a good idea to exercise for at least 20 minutes in the morning on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\n5- Taichi\nAs Jane Collins, taichi also is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. TaichiA2Z is the best site to learn Yang taichi or Wudang tai chi.\n6- Change your life style:\nAs Jane Collins, you should: do not work overtime, do not smoke, do not sleep late, sleep more, quit smoking.\n7- Yoga\nAs Jane Collins, yoga is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. YogaHandbook365 is a good site to learn many styles of yoga.\n>>Useful sources:\n1- Wikipedia: Best places to learn more high blood pressure.\n2- Best list: 21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "2d778117", "question": "How do I control blood pressure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2eada6f2", "question": "After a period of a year with a slightly high blood pressure (140/90), if an artery was affected badly because of high blood pressure during this period, would the artery recover when blood pressure becomes normal?", "answers": "You’ve read too many spectacular misreporting by the tabloids, one year of having a blood pressure of 140/90 mmHg won’t cause “badly affected arteries”, in fact nothing noticeable at all.\nMost people are erroneously alarmed having read spectacular tabloid headlines like this, not having read the paper by themselves\nThese tabloids “forgot” to mention that is was a study done in people >50 yo with at least one risk factor for cardiovascular disease, so not applicable to most readers.\nHaving a “perfect” blood pressure of 120/80 mmHg doesn’t guarrantee you’ll never will die of IHD = ischemic heart disease, a higher age raises the risk more than slightly elevated blood pressure does, from Age-specific relevance of usual\nblood\npressure to vascular mortality: a meta-analysis of individual data for one million adults in 61 prospective s... - PubMed - NCBI"}
{"_id": "6c903d28", "question": "Can a headache increase your blood pressure, or can blood pressure changes cause a headache?", "answers": "I am Martha Nguyen. I would like to share some high blood pressure tricks from Rose Campbell’s website: Top 8 tips that can help to lower your high blood pressure in just 9 mins. Rose Campbell is a famous blogger about blood pressure.\nRose Campbell’s Tip 1: Lose weight. Being overweight means that your heart has to pump blood to a larger body mass, which makes the heart work harder. Losing weight reduces the workload. “Plus, your heart will be better able to respond to circumstances that do require more work, like exercise,” says Dr. Zusman.\nRose Campbell’s Tip 2: Exercise. Any activity that gets your heart pumping faster and your lungs working harder is one of the best ways to lower high blood pressure. “It improves the blood vessels’ ability to open and close, which improves blood flow,” says Dr. Zusman. Aim for at least 150 minutes of moderate-intensity activity per week, such as brisk walking.\nRose Campbell’s Tip 3: Reduce your stress. Chronic stress may contribute to high blood pressure. More research is needed to determine the effects of chronic stress on blood pressure. Occasional stress also can contribute to high blood pressure if you react to stress by eating unhealthy food, drinking alcohol or smoking.\nRose Campbell’s Tip 4: Reduce sodium in your diet\nRose Campbell’s Tip 5: Control underlying conditions.\nRose Campbell’s Tip 6: Stop caffeine.\nRose Campbell’s Tip 7: Limit alcohol intake.\nRose Campbell’s Tip 8: Stop smoking.\nUseful resources:\n1- Wikipedia: Hypertension - Wikipedia\n2- HypertensionTips68: Exercise tips for\nhigh\nblood\npressure\n3- Yoga solution from Quora: What are best yoga to control blood pressure?\n4- HBPtips365: 21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "a302eef2", "question": "What is the physiology of high blood pressure? Why are some people more prone than others?", "answers": "TOP 6 WAYS TO LOWER YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE WITHOUT MEDICATION!\nMy name is Carmen Gonzales. I want to share some high blood pressure tips from Anne Gutierrez’s Facebook as followings. Anne Gutierrez is a famous doctor in Anaheim hospital, USA.\n1- Change your diet: According to Anne Gutierrez’s advice, if you follow a good diet, you can reduce your blood pressure by up to 14mmhg.\n2- Lower your stress level:\nAs Anne Gutierrez, stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores so, it's so important that you get some time off and reduce your stress. MeditationSecretsAZ is a good site to learn medation and eiminate your stress\n3- Walk and exercise regularly:\nAs Anne Gutierrez, it's a good idea to exercise for at least 25 minutes in the morning on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\n4- Yoga\nAs Anne Gutierrez, yoga is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. YogaHandbook365 is a good site to learn many styles of yoga.\n5- Change your life style:\nAs Anne Gutierrez, you should: do not work overtime, do not smoke, do not sleep late, sleep more, quit smoking.\n6- Taichi\nAs Anne Gutierrez, taichi also is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. TaichiA2Z is the best site to learn Yang taichi or Wudang tai chi.\n>>Useful sources:\n1- Exercise methods: 22 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure\n2- Wikipedia: Best places to learn more high blood pressure."}
{"_id": "e671dcab", "question": "What diseases are caused by high blood pressure?", "answers": "My name is Tammy Howard. I want to share some high blood pressure techniques from Crystal Wood’s WordPress blog: Top 8 tips that can help to lower your high blood pressure in just 9 mins. Crystal Wood is a famous blogger about blood pressure.\nCrystal Wood’s Tip 1: Lose weight. Being overweight means that your heart has to pump blood to a larger body mass, which makes the heart work harder. Losing weight reduces the workload. “Plus, your heart will be better able to respond to circumstances that do require more work, like exercise,” says Dr. Zusman.\nCrystal Wood’s Tip 2: Exercise. Any activity that gets your heart pumping faster and your lungs working harder is one of the best ways to lower high blood pressure. “It improves the blood vessels’ ability to open and close, which improves blood flow,” says Dr. Zusman. Aim for at least 150 minutes of moderate-intensity activity per week, such as brisk walking.\nCrystal Wood’s Tip 3: Reduce your stress. Chronic stress may contribute to high blood pressure. More research is needed to determine the effects of chronic stress on blood pressure. Occasional stress also can contribute to high blood pressure if you react to stress by eating unhealthy food, drinking alcohol or smoking.\nCrystal Wood’s Tip 4: Reduce sodium in your diet\nCrystal Wood’s Tip 5: Control underlying conditions.\nCrystal Wood’s Tip 6: Stop caffeine.\nCrystal Wood’s Tip 7: Limit alcohol intake.\nCrystal Wood’s Tip 8: Stop smoking.\nUseful resources:\n1- Wikipedia: Hypertension - Wikipedia\n2- HypertensionTips68: Exercise tips for\nhigh\nblood\npressure\n3- Yoga solution from Quora: What are best yoga to control blood pressure?\n4- HBPtips365: 21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "dd125383", "question": "What causes heart flutterings in high blood pressure?", "answers": "BEST 7 NATURAL WAYS TO TREAT YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE!\nMy name is Erika Luna. I would like to share some high blood pressure tips from Monica Vasquez’s Facebook as followings. Monica Vasquez is a famous doctor in Columbus hospital, USA.\n1- Change your diet: According to Monica Vasquez’s advice, There is good evidence plant-based diets high in fruits, vegetables, whole grains and legumes will lead to lower weight loss and blood pressure up to 14mmhg.\nBest foods for high blood pressure:\n-Red beets\n-Skim milk and yogurt\n-Oatmealf\n-Bananas\n-Salmon, mackerel, and fish with omega-3s\n-Seeds\n-Garlic and herbs\n-Dark chocolate\n-Pistachios\n-Olive oil\n-Pomegranates\n-Leafy greens\n-Berries\n2- Eat less.\nAs Monica Vasquez, Up to a certain point, getting thinner will reduce your blood pressure. Bigger mass = bigger body to pump things through = higher blood pressure.\n3- Lower your stress level:\nAs Monica Vasquez, stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores so, it's so important that you get some time off and reduce your stress. MeditationSecretsAZ is a good site to learn medation and eiminate your stress.\n4- Walk and exercise regularly:\nAs Monica Vasquez, it's a good idea to exercise for at least 20 minutes in the morning on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\n5- Taichi\nAs Monica Vasquez, taichi also is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. TaichiA2Z is the best site to learn Yang taichi or Wudang tai chi.\n6- Change your life style:\nAs Monica Vasquez, you should: do not work overtime, do not smoke, do not sleep late, sleep more, quit smoking.\n7- Yoga\nAs Monica Vasquez, yoga is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. YogaHandbook365 is a good site to learn many styles of yoga.\n>>Useful sources:\n1- Wikipedia: Best places to learn more high blood pressure.\n2- Best list: 21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "ecb26ead", "question": "What if we take high blood pressure tablets when we are having low blood pressure?", "answers": "The reason why their blood pressure has stabilized may be due to those meds so unless they are dizzy or syncopal they should not stop the medicine and always consult their practitioner if they are having symptoms which are making them uncomfortable because it may be unrelated to the anti-hypertensive medication.\nIf a person was never hypertensive in the first place lowering the blood pressure may cause them to have difficulty mentating or they may pass out and hurt themselves. Poor cardiac profusion or profusion to the kidneys may also cause havoc."}
{"_id": "82c31f31", "question": "Are high blood pressure and high cholesterol linked?", "answers": "BEST 7 NATURAL WAYS TO TREAT YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE!\nI am Belinda Holland. I want to share some high blood pressure tricks from Hazel Graham’s website as follows. Hazel Graham is a famous doctor in Boston hospital, USA.\n1- Change your diet: According to Hazel Graham’s advice, There is good evidence plant-based diets high in fruits, vegetables, whole grains and legumes will lead to lower weight loss and blood pressure up to 14mmhg.\nBest foods for high blood pressure:\n-Red beets\n-Skim milk and yogurt\n-Oatmealf\n-Bananas\n-Salmon, mackerel, and fish with omega-3s\n-Seeds\n-Garlic and herbs\n-Dark chocolate\n-Pistachios\n-Olive oil\n-Pomegranates\n-Leafy greens\n-Berries\n2- Eat less.\nAs Hazel Graham, Up to a certain point, getting thinner will reduce your blood pressure. Bigger mass = bigger body to pump things through = higher blood pressure.\n3- Lower your stress level:\nAs Hazel Graham, stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores so, it's so important that you get some time off and reduce your stress. MeditationSecretsAZ is a good site to learn medation and eiminate your stress.\n4- Walk and exercise regularly:\nAs Hazel Graham, it's a good idea to exercise for at least 20 minutes in the morning on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\n5- Taichi\nAs Hazel Graham, taichi also is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. TaichiA2Z is the best site to learn Yang taichi or Wudang tai chi.\n6- Change your life style:\nAs Hazel Graham, you should: do not work overtime, do not smoke, do not sleep late, sleep more, quit smoking.\n7- Yoga\nAs Hazel Graham, yoga is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. YogaHandbook365 is a good site to learn many styles of yoga.\n>>Useful sources:\n1- Wikipedia: Best places to learn more high blood pressure.\n2- Best list: 21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "02898bb6", "question": "Is high blood pressure a silent killer?", "answers": "Livedia palace, in Crimea, Yalta, located in southern Ukraine, at the shores of Black Sea, was the summer retreat of Russian Tsar, Nicholas II. With 116 rooms, each one furnished in different taste and design it was the ultimate in opulence. It was here that on February 4, 1945, the big three world leaders met.\nThe British Prime Minister Sir Winston Churchill, the American President Franklin D Roosevelt, and Chairman Of Russian Federation, Joseph Stalin, the trio finally decided to draw the curtain on to one of the bloodiest of human conflicts, the second world war. While they conferred and mediated to end the animosity, unknown to these three men, a common enemy was on their job, working silently, planning a sinister personal attack on each one of them, an attack of a different kind. Hypertension.\nExactly 68 days later, President Franklin D Roosevelt died of a massive cerebral hemorrhage. Joseph Stalin in 1953 and Sir Winston Churchill in 1966, died from cerebral stroke. All the three world leaders succumbed to the complication of a totally preventable disease - high blood pressure, ‘hypertension’ in medical terms.\nThe most important strategy in a war is an early and clear understanding of the sting and reach of this silent enemy. Till recently, doctors failed to do so as far as ‘hypertension’ was concerned. As recent as 1931, the British Medical Journal (BMJ) editorial warned “The greatest danger to man with high blood pressure lies in its discovery, because then some fool is certain to try and reduce it…..”\nFor two long years preceding President Roosevelt’s death, his physicians recorded the President’s blood pressure as high as 200/110 many times, (severe hypertension by today’s standards) but never felt alarmed. On 13th April 1945, the day after President’s death, his physician issued a statement that ‘his death came out of clear sky’ meaning that there was no warning at all. At that time no one thought that this level of blood pressure was abnormal and could cause a brain hemorrhage or stroke. This lack of human understanding of its long term complications, is what makes high blood pressure unique.\nHypertension is often referred to as a disease of 50%! Actually this denotes that only about 50% people with high blood pressure are aware of it, of those aware, only 50% are treated, and of those lucky ones being treated, only 50% are controlled to the recommended goal. In India it is a dismal 30% instead of the western 50%. Stroke, brain hemorrhage, loss of vision, heart attack, bulging of vessels in the chest (aneurysm), kidney failure, you name it and all of them are listed as the complications of hypertension.\nOne major problem of hypertension detection, unlike other diseases, is that it has hardly any symptoms; silent. Majority of patients with high blood pressure don’t have headache or vision problem or get angry or annoyed soon, despite popular belief to the contrary. This means there are hardly any warning signs. The victim can easily be an apparently healthy, you or me. So the only way out is to get our pressures checked and know our numbers.\nIt takes less than 5 minutes for a medical professional to record blood pressure. Undetected high blood pressure can result in a massive brain hemorrhage and kill a person instantly. Even if the victim survives the stroke, the social and economic implications of living with a stroke related disability is even more painful. The December Issue of ‘Lancet’ quotes the Global Burden of Disease (GDB 2010) database to show that high blood pressure ranks as the number one risk factor responsible for death and disability worldwide.\nAll that we request is just 5 minutes of your time. In return you might benefit by decades of healthy future. Call it a short cut to good health, if you wish."}
{"_id": "f2c0bec9", "question": "Does fasting help lower your blood pressure?", "answers": "My name is Barbara Brown. I want to share some high blood pressure secrets from Tina Kelly’s site: Top 10 ways that can help to treat your high blood pressure. Tina Kelly is a famous blogger about blood pressure.\nTina Kelly’s Method 1. Change your diet: If you follow a good diet, you can reduce your blood pressure by up to 14mmHg.\nMethod 2. Control your weight. If you are overweight, losing even a few pounds like 4 kgs can help a lot.\nMethod 3. Walk and exercise regularly. It is a good method to exercise for at least 30 mins on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\nUseful source: Excercise tips to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure\nTina Kelly’s Method 4. Use less salt: According to doctors, you should not take more than 1.4 grams of salt per day so that you may want to use salt sparingly to keep your blood pressure normal.\nMethod 5. Lower your stress level.\nMethod 6. You need to religiously take your maintenance medications to control your hypertension as your doctor has prescribed it.\nMethod 7. Quit smoking.\nMethod 8. Drink less alcohol.\nMethod 9. Eat more potassium-rich foods.\nMethod 10. Cut back on caffeine."}
{"_id": "8073ccd9", "question": "Can ibuprofen be taken if I have high blood pressure?", "answers": "BEST 10 NATURAL WAYS TO CURE YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE!\nI am Doris Diaz. I found some high blood pressure methods from Tiffany Alvarez’s Twitter as follows. Tiffany Alvarez is a famous doctor in Buffalo hospital, USA.\n1- Exercise regularly. According to Tiffany Alvarez’s advice, 150 minutes of walking or 75 minutes of running weekly can help lower blood pressure and improve your heart health.\nSome exercises for high blood pressure:\nGo for a Swim.\n+ Take a Walk.\n+ Ride a Bike.\n+ Hit the Gym.\n+ Yoga\n2. Lose weight if you are overweight\nAs Tiffany Alvarez, A 2017 review of Harvard Health studies reported that weight loss diets reduced blood pressure by an average of 3.2 mm Hg diastolic and 4.5 mm Hg systolic.\n3- Reduce your sodium intake.\nAs Tiffany Alvarez, If you already have high blood pressure, it is worth cutting back your sodium intake to see if it makes a difference. In many studies, salt has been linked to high blood pressure and heart events, like stroke.\n4- Learn to manage stress.\nAs Tiffany Alvarez, Stress is a key source of high blood pressure. MeditationHandbook888 is the best site to learn how to stop stress and learn mediation.\n5. Yoga\nAs Tiffany Alvarez, Yoga is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure.\n7. Taichi\nAs Tiffany Alvarez, Taichi also is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure.\n7- Make sure to get good, restful sleep\nAs Tiffany Alvarez, Your blood pressure typically dips down when you are sleeping. If you don not sleep well, it can affect your blood pressure.\n>>Useful resources:\n1- Exercises methods: Best 3 exercises to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure in 9 minutes\n2- 42HBPmethods is the good blog to read the list of 42 ways to cure high blood presssure."}
{"_id": "818afcf5", "question": "Does high blood pressure lead to dementia?", "answers": "I am June Boyd. Hi friends, let me show some high blood pressure tricks from Tara Schmidt’s website: Top 8 tips that can help to lower your high blood pressure in just 9 mins. Tara Schmidt is a famous blogger about blood pressure.\nTara Schmidt’s Tip 1: Lose weight. Being overweight means that your heart has to pump blood to a larger body mass, which makes the heart work harder. Losing weight reduces the workload. “Plus, your heart will be better able to respond to circumstances that do require more work, like exercise,” says Dr. Zusman.\nTara Schmidt’s Tip 2: Exercise. Any activity that gets your heart pumping faster and your lungs working harder is one of the best ways to lower high blood pressure. “It improves the blood vessels’ ability to open and close, which improves blood flow,” says Dr. Zusman. Aim for at least 150 minutes of moderate-intensity activity per week, such as brisk walking.\nTara Schmidt’s Tip 3: Reduce your stress. Chronic stress may contribute to high blood pressure. More research is needed to determine the effects of chronic stress on blood pressure. Occasional stress also can contribute to high blood pressure if you react to stress by eating unhealthy food, drinking alcohol or smoking.\nTara Schmidt’s Tip 4: Reduce sodium in your diet\nTara Schmidt’s Tip 5: Control underlying conditions.\nTara Schmidt’s Tip 6: Stop caffeine.\nTara Schmidt’s Tip 7: Limit alcohol intake.\nTara Schmidt’s Tip 8: Stop smoking.\nUseful resources:\n1- Wikipedia: Hypertension - Wikipedia\n2- HypertensionTips68: Exercise tips for\nhigh\nblood\npressure\n3- Yoga solution from Quora: What are best yoga to control blood pressure?\n4- HBPtips365: 21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "5dc91d58", "question": "How can we reduce blood pressure without tablets?", "answers": "TOP 10 NATURAL WAYS TO CURE YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE.\nMy name is Mildred Reyes. I would like to share some high blood pressure techniques from Jean Flores’s WordPress blog as followings. Jean Flores is a famous doctor.\nBEST FOODS FOR HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE RECOMMENDED BY HARVARD HEALTH:\n1- Leafy greens\n2- Berries\n3- Red beets\n4- Skim milk and yogurt\n5- Oatmeal\n6- Bananas\n7- Salmon, mackerel, and fish with omega-3s\n8- Seeds\n9- Garlic and herbs\n10- Dark chocolate\n11- Pistachios\n12- Olive oil\n13- Pomegranates\nJean Flores also shares some useful tips below:\n1. Walk and exercise regularly\nAs Jean Flores, Regular exercise helps make your heart stronger and more efficient at pumping blood, which lowers the pressure in your arteries. In fact, 150 minutes of moderate exercise, such as walking, or 75 minutes of vigorous exercise, such as running, per week can help lower blood pressure and improve your heart health. Useful source: Top 3 exercises to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure\n2. Reduce your sodium intake\nAs Jean Flores, Salt intake is high around the world. In large part, this is due to processed and prepared foods. In many studies, salt has been linked to high blood pressure and heart events, like stroke. If you already have high blood pressure, it's worth cutting back your sodium intake to see if it makes a difference. Swap out processed foods with fresh ones and try seasoning with herbs and spices, rather than salt.\n3. Drink less alcohol\nAs Jean Flores, Drinking alcohol can raise blood pressure. In fact, alcohol is linked to 16% of high blood pressure cases around the world.While some research has suggested that low-to-moderate amounts of alcohol may protect the heart, those benefits may be offset by negative effects.\n4. Eat more potassium-rich foods\nAs Jean Flores, Potassium is an important mineral. It helps your body get rid of sodium and ease pressure on your blood vessels. To get a better balance of potassium to sodium in your diet, focus on eating fewer processed foods and more fresh, whole foods.\n5. Cut back on caffeine\nAs Jean Flores, If you've ever downed a cup of coffee before you've had your blood pressure taken, you'll know that caffeine causes an instant boost. If you suspect you're caffeine-sensitive, cut back to see if it lowers your blood pressure (20Trusted Source).\n6. Learn to manage stress\nAs Jean Flores, Stress is a key driver of high blood pressure. When you're chronically stressed, your body is in a constant fight-or-flight mode. On a physical level, that means a faster heart rate and constricted blood vessels. When you experience stress, you might also be more likely to engage in other behaviors, such as drinking alcohol or eating unhealthy food, that can negatively affect blood pressure.\n7. Lose weight\nAs Jean Flores, If you're overweight, losing weight can make a big difference for your heart health. According to a 2016 study, losing 5% of your body mass could significantly lower high blood pressure. In previous studies, losing 17 pounds (7.7 kg) was linked to lowering systolic blood pressure by 8.5 mm Hg and diastolic blood pressure by 6.5 mm Hg (28Trusted Source).\n8. Try meditation or deep breathing\nAs Jean Flores, While these two behaviors could also fall under \"stress reduction techniques,\" meditation and deep breathing deserve specific mention. Both meditation and deep breathing are thought to activate the parasympathetic nervous system. This system is engaged when the body relaxes, slowing the heart rate and lowering blood pressure.\n9. Cut added sugar and refined carbs\nAs Jean Flores, There's a growing body of research showing a link between added sugar and high blood pressure. In the Framingham Women's Health Study, women who drank even one soda per day had higher levels than those who drank less than one soda per day. Another study found that having one less sugar-sweetened beverage per day was linked to lower blood pressure.\n10. Eat berries\nAs Jean Flores, Berries are full of more than just juicy flavor. They're also packed with polyphenols, natural plant compounds that are good for your heart. One small study had middle-aged people eat berries for eight weeks. Participants experienced improvements in different markers of heart health, including blood pressure.\nUseful resource:\n-Wikipedia: Hypertension - Wikipedia\n-21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "43e9997d", "question": "Is too much exercise a cause of high blood pressure? Veins in hands are caused by too much exercise, which results in high blood pressure, but is too much exercise a direct cause to high blood pressure?", "answers": "BEST 7 NATURAL WAYS TO TREAT YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE!\nMy name is Nora Harvey. I want to share some high blood pressure tips from Cindy Patel’s Facebook below. Cindy Patel is a famous doctor in Reno hospital, USA.\n1- Change your diet: According to Cindy Patel’s advice, There is good evidence plant-based diets high in fruits, vegetables, whole grains and legumes will lead to lower weight loss and blood pressure up to 14mmhg.\nBest foods for high blood pressure:\n-Red beets\n-Skim milk and yogurt\n-Oatmealf\n-Bananas\n-Salmon, mackerel, and fish with omega-3s\n-Seeds\n-Garlic and herbs\n-Dark chocolate\n-Pistachios\n-Olive oil\n-Pomegranates\n-Leafy greens\n-Berries\n2- Eat less.\nAs Cindy Patel, Up to a certain point, getting thinner will reduce your blood pressure. Bigger mass = bigger body to pump things through = higher blood pressure.\n3- Lower your stress level:\nAs Cindy Patel, stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores so, it's so important that you get some time off and reduce your stress. MeditationSecretsAZ is a good site to learn medation and eiminate your stress.\n4- Walk and exercise regularly:\nAs Cindy Patel, it's a good idea to exercise for at least 20 minutes in the morning on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\n5- Taichi\nAs Cindy Patel, taichi also is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. TaichiA2Z is the best site to learn Yang taichi or Wudang tai chi.\n6- Change your life style:\nAs Cindy Patel, you should: do not work overtime, do not smoke, do not sleep late, sleep more, quit smoking.\n7- Yoga\nAs Cindy Patel, yoga is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. YogaHandbook365 is a good site to learn many styles of yoga.\n>>Useful sources:\n1- Wikipedia: Best places to learn more high blood pressure.\n2- Best list: 21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "d3f9d7e1", "question": "Is having high blood pressure considered having heart problems?", "answers": "Both high blood pressure and heart problems are inter related disease processes…and having high blood pressure usually means your general circulatory system is “ in poor shape ….I am talking about the majority of cases of high blood pressure in people…( unknown cause)….and omit discussing the other “ known cause of high BP)….like kidney problems or other secondary causes.\nIn the majority of cases,one develops high BP for many years and if left untreated ( because high BP cause little or no symptoms)…heart disease follows.You can imagine that in high bp the inner walls of your blood vessels are under high pressure thus wear and tear of this lining is increased greatly) and the media size vessels in your heart will begin to become damaged..causing narrowing and heart problems from poor circulation of heart muscle….also increase in bp over many years causes the heart ( the pump) to become overworked..and can increase the size of heart muscle leading to hear failure.\nThe big picture is of a person with not just one illness but multiple issues going on,like poor diet,stress,poor lifestyle with high saturated fat foods,little exercise,poor sleep, obesity,high lipids and borderline elevated blood sugar levels……\nthe short answer is yes…you can consider that if you have a diagnosis of high bp,you will have some degree of heart problems…and need to consider all the risks I mentioned and begin to take charge of your health…."}
{"_id": "58027e6c", "question": "Why does sodium increase blood pressure?", "answers": "Salt / Sodium Effects On Blood Pressure And Brain to kidney >\nSalt works on your kidneys to make your body hold on to more water.\nThis extra stored water raises your blood pressure and puts strain on your kidneys, arteries, heart and brain.\nKidneys\nArteries\nHear\nt\nbrain\nYour body removes unwanted fluid by filtering your blood through your kidneys. Here any extra fluid is sucked out and put into your bladder to be removed as urine.\nTo do this, your kidneys use osmosis to draw the extra water out of your blood. This process uses a delicate balance of sodium and potassium to pull the water across a wall of cells from the bloodstream into a collecting channel that leads to the bladder.\nEating salt raises the amount of sodium in your bloodstream and wrecks the delicate balance, reducing the ability of your kidneys to remove the water.\nThe result is a higher blood pressure due to the extra fluid and extra strain on the delicate blood vessels leading to the kidneys.\nOver time, this extra strain causes damage the kidneys - known as kidney disease. This reduces their ability to filter out unwanted and toxic waste products, which then start to build up in the body.\nIf kidney disease is left untreated and the blood pressure isn't lowered, the damage can lead to kidney failure. This is when the kidneys are no longer able to be filter the blood and the body slowly becomes poisoned by its own toxic waste products.\nThese five condiments top the list of salt traps:\nKetchup & BBQ sauce\nWe know that there’s a lot of sugar in ketchup – and unlike what Ronald Reagan once said, it doesn’t count as a serving of vegetables! But the salt factor in ketchup is also something to consider. One tablespoon of ketchup – about what you might put on your hotdog at a hockey game from one of those little packets – clocks in at 167 mg of sodium. That’s 7% of the daily recommended dose for an adult. For a child, well it’s not hard to do the math when most dietitians recommend no sodium for kids at all.\nMustard\nA serving of mustard, that other street-meat condiment, has around the same amount of sodium as ketchup– 150 mg. And those fancy French Dijon mustards from France don’t change a thing. Most contain about 120 mg.\n…just in case you’. It also contains over 100mg per tablespoon.\nHot Sauce\nOne teaspoon can clock in as high as 120 mg of salt –not as “hot” as one might think. But we must admit, a little goes a long way. If you like it hot, you can always try a couple of shakes of chillies into your cooking instead.\nSoy Sauce\nFinally, the very condiment that is often used to replace table salt is another super-carrier: Soy sauce. Just one tablespoon has over 900 mg of sodium – that’s almost half your daily intake! Even reduced-sodium soy sauce contains over 500 mg. How about making your own peanut sauce, or squeezing a little lemon on your food?\nSalad dressing\nEating a healthy salad? Good job! Now, check the sodium content of what you’ve smothered on top: Italian salad dressing contains 430 milligrams in just 2 tablespoons! You’ll likely use at least that. – Maybe try a little lemon , and herbs , balsamic vinegar instead\nToday’s food culture of being able to eat whatever we want, whenever we want has made it difficult for people to limit their intakes, which has led to two-thirds of Americans being overweight. Like an alcoholic or smoker who is trying to quit, advising them to just have one drink or one cigarette a day will do little to eliminate the cravings or the overall habit; it will only leave them frustrated, with that taste still in their mouth, wanting more. Giving up salt, oil and/or sugar can feel the same way for many people, a state that TrueNorth Health Center calls “The Pleasure Trap.\nSOS/salt oils/sugar\nNutritionally speaking, we do not need to add salt, oil and sugar to our food; we can get all the sodium, fat and sugar we need, and in their best forms, from eating a whole-food, plant-based diet\n. The body’s actual need for sodium and essential fats are in fact pretty low (less than the amount of sodium in ¼ teaspoon of salt a day and less than 10% of daily calories from fat), so we don’t need to supplement with any added salt and oil."}
{"_id": "af6585ac", "question": "Is stress the cause of high blood pressure?", "answers": "STRESS! A phenomenon that you suffer from during your daily hustle owing to a haphazard work-pressure, unbalanced schedule without any ME-time! Often, we want to take a break, we want to escape the exhaustion but there’s no beating that as you grow to take more responsibilities, both professionally and personally. Having said that, we are all aware of the impacts that stress has on us, including poor physical, mental and social health. Today, we shall primarily talk about stress and its consequences which include chronic diseases like hypertension and diabetes. But first, let’s get to know the effects of stress on our health.\nHow Can Stress Affect Your Health?\nStress develops over time. Be it a haphazard schedule, over due work load or personal problems - anything that worries you, becomes a part of mental health and the same goes for your physical health when you are constantly hustling to make your mark. The cause can be whatever depending upon your lifestyle, but the impact remains grave.\nHaving a stressed schedule can deteriorate your mental health and can affect your hormonal balance. It can also promote high levels of cortisol which can affect your physical health as well. Poor mental health can affect your physical health as well and can lead to grave disorders for a lifetime including hypertension and diabetes as it affects your internal physique massively.\nIs Hypertension A Consequence of Stress?\nIn the majority of cases, yes! Heavy stress can affect your hormones and can affect the blood circulation as it tampers with your heart rate and respiration rate. As a consequence, the blood pressure elevates and when it becomes a regular part of your life, it takes up the shape of chronic hypertension which in turn remains there for life. This condition is known as Hypertension where your body has high blood pressure throughout its blood vessels and should be regularly managed to avoid consequences like a cardiac attack and neuromuscular damage with stroke.\nCan Ayurveda Help In Dealing With Stress and Hypertension?\nAyurveda, when taken as a lifestyle, can also help with precautions and is an ideal way to battle against diseases that originate from stress - be it physical or mental. Elements of ancient health including that of Panchkarma and DHyana can help you deal with physical and mental health respectively. A brief insight on your schedule with an organizational approach can also help you loads and as a result, you shall feel much relaxed than what you have felt in earlier times. Reducing stress can help you out in protecting yourself against these diseases as well. However, if you are already battling Hypertension, here are a few Ayurvedic remedies that can work wonders for you.\nHypertension can be easily managed with herbs like Shankhavali, Ashwagandha, and Khurasni. If you are looking forward to dealing with your mental stress, Shankhapushpi, and Brahmi are your go to herbs. However, these herbs only contribute to declining your stress levels in both aspects. In case you are having trouble managing your Hypertension or high blood pressure, it is ideal that you go for specifically curated Ayurvedic remedies Like Dr. Vaidya’s Unmadvati. Infused with herbs like Vekhand and Shatavari in addition to the above mentioned herbs, it helps in restoring your natural health while battling the consequences of hypertension."}
{"_id": "62fec482", "question": "Why do I have such high blood pressure?", "answers": "TOP 7 NATURAL METHODS TO CURE YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE!\nI am Frances Campbell. I want to share some high blood pressure experience from Bonnie Cooper’s blog in the following. Bonnie Cooper is a famous registered nurse in Lexington hospital, USA.\n1- Exercise regularly. According to Bonnie Cooper’s advice, Walking 30 minutes daily can lower your blood pressure up to 10 points.\nBest exercise for high blood pressure:\n-walking,\n-swimming,\n-running,\n-biking\n-gym.\n2- Limit your salt usage.\nAs Bonnie Cooper, Cutting the salt in your diet can improve your high blood pressure by up to 9 mmHg.\n3- Maintain an active lifestyle and healthy weight::\nAs Bonnie Cooper, Even if you are busy or out of shape, get out there! One expert urges at least 30 minutes of activity whether it is a brisk walk or intense cardio each day.\n4- Meditation:\nAs Bonnie Cooper, A Harvard Health study found 8 weeks of mindfulness meditation can help to lower high blood pressure. MeditationSecretsAZ .info is a good site for learning.\n5- Taichi\nAs Bonnie Cooper, taichi also is one of the best exercise method to cure high blood pressure in long time. TaichiA2Z .club is the best site to learn Yang taichi or Wudang tai chi.\n6- Change your life style:\nAs Bonnie Cooper, you should: do not sleep late, sleep more, quit smoking, do not work overtime, do not smoke.\n7- Yoga\nAs Bonnie Cooper, yoga is one of the best exercise way to cure high blood pressure in long time. YogaHandbook365 .info is a good site to learn many styles of yoga.\n>>Useful sources:\n1- Wikipedia: Best sites to learn more high blood pressure.\n2- Best list: 27 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "bafac3bf", "question": "Are there some medicines that can cause high blood pressure?", "answers": "I am Nicole Ortiz. I would like to share some high blood pressure tricks from Paula Kim’s website: Top 8 tips that can help to lower your high blood pressure in just 9 mins. Paula Kim is a famous blogger about blood pressure.\nPaula Kim’s Tip 1: Lose weight. Being overweight means that your heart has to pump blood to a larger body mass, which makes the heart work harder. Losing weight reduces the workload. “Plus, your heart will be better able to respond to circumstances that do require more work, like exercise,” says Dr. Zusman.\nPaula Kim’s Tip 2: Exercise. Any activity that gets your heart pumping faster and your lungs working harder is one of the best ways to lower high blood pressure. “It improves the blood vessels’ ability to open and close, which improves blood flow,” says Dr. Zusman. Aim for at least 150 minutes of moderate-intensity activity per week, such as brisk walking.\nPaula Kim’s Tip 3: Reduce your stress. Chronic stress may contribute to high blood pressure. More research is needed to determine the effects of chronic stress on blood pressure. Occasional stress also can contribute to high blood pressure if you react to stress by eating unhealthy food, drinking alcohol or smoking.\nPaula Kim’s Tip 4: Reduce sodium in your diet\nPaula Kim’s Tip 5: Control underlying conditions.\nPaula Kim’s Tip 6: Stop caffeine.\nPaula Kim’s Tip 7: Limit alcohol intake.\nPaula Kim’s Tip 8: Stop smoking.\nUseful resources:\n1- Wikipedia: Hypertension - Wikipedia\n2- HypertensionTips68: Exercise tips for\nhigh\nblood\npressure\n3- Yoga solution from Quora: What are best yoga to control blood pressure?\n4- HBPtips365: 21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "9f5690db", "question": "Why are high blood pressure patients given drips containing sodium, when sodium is supposed to cause high blood pressure?", "answers": "Why are high blood pressure patients given drips containing sodium, when sodium is supposed to cause high blood pressure?\nSodium is an essential element - if we do not have enough of it, we die. Most often, the sodium given in the IV fluid is the same concentration as what is in our bodies. If the IV is being given to replace lost fluids or lost sodium, it is not likely to affect the blood pressure of someone with hypertension (high blood pressure) because you are just replacing what they already had.\nIf too much IV fluid is given to someone with some kinds of kidney disease or some kinds of heart disease, their blood pressure can go up but in these instances it is usually because of the volume of fluid, not the salt that is in it."}
{"_id": "64ff5504", "question": "Is it OK to walk with high blood pressure?", "answers": "My name is Kay Howell. Let me share some high blood pressure tips from Jeanie English’s Facebook: Top 8 tips that can help to lower your high blood pressure in just 9 mins. Jeanie English is a famous blogger about blood pressure.\nJeanie English’s Tip 1: Lose weight. Being overweight means that your heart has to pump blood to a larger body mass, which makes the heart work harder. Losing weight reduces the workload. “Plus, your heart will be better able to respond to circumstances that do require more work, like exercise,” says Dr. Zusman.\nJeanie English’s Tip 2: Exercise. Any activity that gets your heart pumping faster and your lungs working harder is one of the best ways to lower high blood pressure. “It improves the blood vessels’ ability to open and close, which improves blood flow,” says Dr. Zusman. Aim for at least 150 minutes of moderate-intensity activity per week, such as brisk walking.\nJeanie English's Tip 3: Reduce your stress. Chronic stress may contribute to high blood pressure. More research is needed to determine the effects of chronic stress on blood pressure. Occasional stress also can contribute to high blood pressure if you react to stress by eating unhealthy food, drinking alcohol or smoking.\nJeanie English's Tip 4: Reduce sodium in your diet\nJeanie English's Tip 5: Control underlying conditions.\nJeanie English's Tip 6: Stop caffeine.\nJeanie English's Tip 7: Limit alcohol intake.\nJeanie English's Tip 8: Stop smoking.\nUseful resources:\n1- Wikipedia: Hypertension - Wikipedia\n2- HypertensionTips68: Exercise tips for\nhigh\nblood\npressure\n3- Yoga solution from Quora: What are best yoga to control blood pressure?\n4- HBPtips365: 21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "6c92c838", "question": "What are the reasons for high blood pressure in a diabetic patient?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ef6c75db", "question": "Could a neck injury produce high blood pressure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "9ca2d720", "question": "Can sinusitis cause high blood pressure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "10f61e24", "question": "What can high blood pressure cause?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2f75dacb", "question": "What if you forget to take high blood pressure medicine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "8c643f21", "question": "Will lack of sleep affect blood sugar?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1b2f8daa", "question": "Is it true that high blood pressure medicine can cause diabetes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6f546e7d", "question": "Does stress cause high Blood Pressure or high blood pressure cause stress?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "df62c81d", "question": "Does ginger juice reduce high blood pressure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e6a642d1", "question": "Does chronic high blood pressure decrease your lifespan?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d0bf1f94", "question": "What is the diet suggested for patients suffering from high blood pressure and diabetes?", "answers": "I can understand your worry. If you are suffering from both blood pressure and diabetes, perhaps both are related. For me, when I could control blood sugar well, my BP seems to be in control without any medication. Of course, your case need not be so.\nThere is no perfect diet. Many diet schemes are available such as low carb diets, high fat diets, fruit diets. Some are fad and dangerous for us. It is better that assess and find a menu which reduces intake of carbohydrates( try to reduce carb intake slowly to less that 150g in total per day). Have a food weighing scale and a carb counting table(download from web). Take less amount of rice, wheat and high carb vegetables. You can take some brown rices of sonamasouri for which glycemic index is low. Always consider taking limited amounts of low glycemic foods. Consult with a capable dietician(very difficult to find in India), and fix the total energy needs and how much to take in each meal considering your medication. Have a decent proportion of carbs, protein and fats. Our food sources should also contain enough micro nutrients which reduces the inflammation load on the body. The following are Joslin’s guideline essentials (shown as approximate percents of daily calories):Diabetes & Diet: A Personalized Approach\nCarbohydrate: 40 percent from carbohydrates, including at least 20-35 grams of fiber. Best carbohydrate/high-fiber sources: fresh vegetables, fruits, beans and whole-grain foods. Eat less of these carbs: pasta, white bread, white potatoes and sugary cereals.\nProtein: 20-30 percent from protein (unless you have kidney disease). Best protein sources: fish, skinless chicken or turkey, nonfat or low-fat dairy products, tofu and legumes (beans and peas).\nFat: 30-35 percent from fat (mostly mono- and polyunsaturated fats). Best fat sources: olive oil, canola oil, nuts, seeds and fatty fish like salmon.\nThere are many other types of dietary recommendations, but you or your doctor is the best judge. Always test for sugar levels before and after 2hrs of taking each type of food. In this way find out what type food is best for you. Use curry leaves, garlic, cinnamon and other spices lavishly. Reduce salt, artificial taste making items and flavours. Grind your curry powders yourself.\nOnce your sugar is in control and High BP persists consult your doctor and take medications. Alternatively some foods are also known to reduce BP(again you need to measure BP regularly and check whether these do have any effect). Regular exercise and yoga will be beneficial for both diabetes and HBP.\nFoods That Lower\nBlood\nPressure\n."}
{"_id": "b8b10ff1", "question": "Which condition is worse, high blood pressure or diabetes, and why?", "answers": "This is a little bit like asking if it is worse to be shot or to be stabbed. They are both dangerous. The common thing about each of them is it is not the conditions themselves that we worry about, but rather what they can do. When uncontrolled, both diabetes and high blood pressure are huge risk factors for heart attack and stroke.\nRemember that there are two forms of diabetes, type 1 and type 2. Type 1 diabetes is a different animal, in that if it is not treated, it is rapidly fatal. I assume you are asking about the far more common type 2 diabetes.\nHigh blood pressure (hypertension) is more likely to be acutely dangerous. If it gets high enough, it can cause acute damage to the heart and kidneys, and can lead to burst blood vessels in the brain. Out of control blood pressure is more likely to land you in the hospital than out of control type 2 diabetes.\nType 2 diabetes is usually not something that causes rapid onset problems, but when not controlled leads to a host of issues with the heart, kidneys, brain, eyes, and nervous system.\nMy general experience is that hypertension is easier to control than type 2 diabetes, most of the time. Diabetics require more comprehensive lifestyle management than h hypertensives do. Also, the great majority of type 2 diabetics also have hypertension, so they get the worst of both worlds as it is."}
{"_id": "d0b5ceb4", "question": "What health problems are associated with high blood pressure?", "answers": "I am Lori Cox. I would like to share some high blood pressure experience from Dawn Gray’s blog: Top 8 tips that can help to lower your high blood pressure in just 9 mins. Dawn Gray is a famous blogger about blood pressure.\nDawn Gray’s Tip 1: Lose weight. Being overweight means that your heart has to pump blood to a larger body mass, which makes the heart work harder. Losing weight reduces the workload. “Plus, your heart will be better able to respond to circumstances that do require more work, like exercise,” says Dr. Zusman.\nDawn Gray’s Tip 2: Exercise. Any activity that gets your heart pumping faster and your lungs working harder is one of the best ways to lower high blood pressure. “It improves the blood vessels’ ability to open and close, which improves blood flow,” says Dr. Zusman. Aim for at least 150 minutes of moderate-intensity activity per week, such as brisk walking.\nDawn Gray’s Tip 3: Reduce your stress. Chronic stress may contribute to high blood pressure. More research is needed to determine the effects of chronic stress on blood pressure. Occasional stress also can contribute to high blood pressure if you react to stress by eating unhealthy food, drinking alcohol or smoking.\nDawn Gray’s Tip 4: Reduce sodium in your diet\nDawn Gray’s Tip 5: Control underlying conditions.\nDawn Gray’s Tip 6: Stop caffeine.\nDawn Gray’s Tip 7: Limit alcohol intake.\nDawn Gray’s Tip 8: Stop smoking.\nUseful resources:\n1- Wikipedia: Hypertension - Wikipedia\n2- HypertensionTips68: Exercise tips for\nhigh\nblood\npressure\n3- Yoga solution from Quora: What are best yoga to control blood pressure?\n4- HBPtips365: 21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "1256a5f1", "question": "Why does high blood pressure cause tinnitus?", "answers": "High Blood pressure can cause tinnitus because as cholesterol and other deposits build up in the major blood vessels close to one’s middle and inner ear they lose some of their elasticity — the ability to flex or expand slightly with each heartbeat. This is called Atherosclerosis\nWhich causes blood flow to become more forceful, making it easier for your ear to detect the beats. You can generally hear this type of tinnitus in both ears.\nThis type of tinnitus is known as pulsatile tinnitus because it ‘pulses’ with the heart rhythm .\nThe good news is that by treating high blood pressure one can lessen the impact of pulsatile tinnitus."}
{"_id": "61d8fdd6", "question": "Can smoking cause high blood pressure?", "answers": "TOP 6 WAYS TO LOWER YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE WITHOUT MEDICATION!\nI am Clara Woods. I would like to share some high blood pressure methods from Kim Jimenez’s Twitter in the following. Kim Jimenez is a famous doctor in North Las Vegas hospital, USA.\n1- Change your diet: According to Kim Jimenez’s advice, if you follow a good diet, you can reduce your blood pressure by up to 14mmhg.\n2- Lower your stress level:\nAs Kim Jimenez, stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores so, it's so important that you get some time off and reduce your stress. MeditationSecretsAZ is a good site to learn medation and eiminate your stress\n3- Walk and exercise regularly:\nAs Kim Jimenez, it's a good idea to exercise for at least 25 minutes in the morning on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\n4- Yoga\nAs Kim Jimenez, yoga is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. YogaHandbook365 is a good site to learn many styles of yoga.\n5- Change your life style:\nAs Kim Jimenez, you should: do not work overtime, do not smoke, do not sleep late, sleep more, quit smoking.\n6- Taichi\nAs Kim Jimenez, taichi also is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. TaichiA2Z is the best site to learn Yang taichi or Wudang tai chi.\n>>Useful sources:\n1- Exercise methods: 22 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure\n2- Wikipedia: Best places to learn more high blood pressure."}
{"_id": "9cc35527", "question": "What are things to do if you have high blood pressure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "63ff1e3b", "question": "Can black seed oil cure high blood pressure?", "answers": "BEST 7 NATURAL WAYS TO TREAT YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE!\nMy name is Meghan Gross. Let me share some high blood pressure tips from Marsha Ortega’s Facebook below. Marsha Ortega is a famous doctor in Wichita hospital, USA.\n1- Change your diet: According to Marsha Ortega’s advice, There is good evidence plant-based diets high in fruits, vegetables, whole grains and legumes will lead to lower weight loss and blood pressure up to 14mmhg.\nBest foods for high blood pressure:\n-Red beets\n-Skim milk and yogurt\n-Oatmealf\n-Bananas\n-Salmon, mackerel, and fish with omega-3s\n-Seeds\n-Garlic and herbs\n-Dark chocolate\n-Pistachios\n-Olive oil\n-Pomegranates\n-Leafy greens\n-Berries\n2- Eat less.\nAs Marsha Ortega, Up to a certain point, getting thinner will reduce your blood pressure. Bigger mass = bigger body to pump things through = higher blood pressure.\n3- Lower your stress level:\nAs Marsha Ortega, stress is a result of the never-ending daily chores so, it's so important that you get some time off and reduce your stress. MeditationSecretsAZ is a good site to learn medation and eiminate your stress.\n4- Walk and exercise regularly:\nAs Marsha Ortega, it's a good idea to exercise for at least 20 minutes in the morning on a regular basis then this can bring the reading down by up to 9 mmHg.\n5- Taichi\nAs Marsha Ortega, taichi also is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. TaichiA2Z is the best site to learn Yang taichi or Wudang tai chi.\n6- Change your life style:\nAs Marsha Ortega, you should: do not work overtime, do not smoke, do not sleep late, sleep more, quit smoking.\n7- Yoga\nAs Marsha Ortega, yoga is one of the best way to lower your high blood pressure. YogaHandbook365 is a good site to learn many styles of yoga.\n>>Useful sources:\n1- Wikipedia: Best places to learn more high blood pressure.\n2- Best list: 21 ways to cure\nhigh\nblood\npressure"}
{"_id": "09e16e21", "question": "Can high blood pressure be cured by increasing the urine output?", "answers": "No.\nBy increasing the urine output high BP cannot be cured.\nBody must maintain the blood volume in tight range. Blood volume must be maintained at 6 to 7% of the body weight. No medicines can reduce reduce the blood volume.\nBody is 70% fluid. Blood is only 10% of the total fluid. 90% of the fluid is there in cells and space between cells. If diuretics reduce the blood volume that will be immediately taken from the cells. If on day 1 the blood volume is reduced by 100 ml. Within 50 days the blood volume will be reduced by 5000 ml. The person will be dead much before this.\nThe analogy given in another answer is based on the wrong assumptions.\nDiuretics force the cells to give up some of the fluids. That eases the situation for some time. Diuretics do not work beyond 4–5 years. Then person has to shift to some other medicines.\nTo cure blood pressure we must understand why there is excess fluid in cells. Reduce the excess fluid in cells naturally and cure high blood pressure.\nThe water that we drink on empty stomach or excess water that we drink with meals reaches in large intestines. Large intestines absorb only water and vitamins. This water gets into cells. That results in low concentration of minerals and other nutrients.\nThe imbalance in minerals in cells causes high blood pressure. The imbalance in minerals can be naturally cured by hydration dehydration cycles and walk and rest routines as mentioned on my Quora profile.\nEvery body should try these natural cures before starting medicines to lower blood pressure. Medicines kill people. Out body is perfect machine. Our misunderstanding and quest to make money causes illness."}
{"_id": "203336a9", "question": "Is a blood pressure of 130/80 high?", "answers": "Blood pressure of 120/80 or above is considered elevated; 130/80 to 139/89 is now considered Stage 1 hypertension and anything 140/90 or above will be considered stage 2 hypertension. ... Previously, people were not considered to have high blood pressure until the top reading hit 140.\nThe new guideline adopts a key component of the 2013 cholesterol guideline and incorporates overall cardiovascular risk. Many people newly defined as hypertensive because they have a systolic blood pressure between 130-139 mm Hg or a diastolic blood pressure between 80-89 mm Hg do not need to take drugs.\nThe new guideline adopts a key component of the 2013 cholesterol guideline and incorporates overall cardiovascular risk. Many people newly defined as hypertensive because they have a systolic blood pressure between 130-139 mm Hg or a diastolic blood pressure between 80-89 mm Hg do not need to take drugs.\nThe previous guidelines set the threshold at 140/90 mm Hg for people younger than age 65 and 150/80 mm Hg for those ages 65 and older. This means 70% to 79% of men ages 55 and older are now classified as having hypertension. That includes many men whose blood pressure had previously been considered healthy.\nA hypertensive crisis is a severe increase in blood pressure that can lead to a stroke. Extremely high blood pressure — a top number (systolic pressure) of 180 millimeters of mercury (mm Hg) or higher or a bottom number (diastolic pressure) of 120 mm Hg or higher — can damage blood vessels."}
{"_id": "7d3206a6", "question": "Should you eat peanut butter if you have high blood pressure?", "answers": "Many peanut butters use hydrogenated vegetable oil to keep it from separating into a layer of liquid and a layer of solid at room temperature. These are saturated fats that create “bad” cholesterols and increase atherosclerosis, or plaque in your arteries, which leads to high blood pressure. Some popular peanut butter brands contain as much as 20% daily value of saturated fat in just 2 tablespoons. You can find peanut butters that don’t use hydrogenated vegetable oil while reading the food label to ensure no saturated fats."}
{"_id": "cdae0508", "question": "Can driving cause high blood pressure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2b4a448d", "question": "Has the keto diet helped your blood test levels? I have high blood pressure and cholesterol and am pre diabetic. Is keto right for me?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e4d5e326", "question": "Which blood pressure medicine has the least side effects?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4808df2e", "question": "Is acupressure effective for high blood pressure problem?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d9e30124", "question": "I have high blood pressure at age of 25. How long can I expect to live?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "811a5e39", "question": "At what level is high blood pressure dangerous?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d436bf03", "question": "Which is more dangerous for the human body between low blood sugar and high blood sugar?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "a5e2e017", "question": "Why is it bad to have high blood pressure?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ab145978", "question": "Can high blood pressure cause itching?", "answers": ""}
